This is Agent Leland Turbo.
我是探员利兰·超动力
I have a flash transmission for Agent Finn McMissile.
紧急呼叫探员芬恩·麦导弹
Finn，my cover's been compromised。Everything's gone pear-shaped.
芬恩，我的身份已经暴露，局面已失控
You won't believe what I found out here.
你猜我在这儿发现了什么？
This is bigger than anything we've ever seen，
我们从来没见过这么大的东西
and no one even knows it exists.
甚至没人知道有这种东西存在
Finn，I need backup，
芬恩，我需要支援
but don't call the cavalry，it could blow the operation.
不过别联络装甲部队，会把行动搞砸的
And be careful。It's not safe out here。Let's go.
你要小心，这里现在不安全
Transmitting my grids now。Good luck.
这就把我的方位传送给你，祝你好运
《赛车总动员2》
All right，buddy，we're here.
好了，兄弟，我们到了
Right where you paid me to bring you.
就是你雇我带你来的地方
Question is，why？
不过你来这儿干嘛？
I'm looking for a car.
我要找一辆车
A car？Ha！
一辆车？哈！
Hey，pal，you can't get any further away from land than out here.
嘿，伙计，这是离陆地最远的地方了
Exactly where I want to be.
这就是我要来的地方
I got news for you，buddy。There's nobody out here but us.
我告诉你吧，这地方除了咱俩就没别人
What are you doing out here？
你在这里干什么？
What does it look like，genius？I'm crabbing.
我还能干什么，老大？我是捕蟹船耶
Well，turn around and go back where you came from.
那就调头，从哪儿来回哪儿去
Yeah，and who's gonna make me？
凭什么，我看谁敢赶我？
All right。All right。Don't get your prop in a twist.
行了，行了，把你的新式武器收起来吧
What a jerk。Sorry，buddy。Looks like it's the end of the line.
真过分！抱歉朋友，看来这就是终点站了
Buddy？
人呢？
Incoming。All workers report to the loading dock.
通知：所有工人上码头报到
Leland Turbo，this is Finn McMissile
芬恩·麦导弹呼叫利兰·超动力
.I'm at the rally point。Over.
我已到达集结地点，完毕
All right，fellas，you know the drill.
好的，伙计们，你们知道规矩
Leland，it's Finn。Please respond。Over.
芬恩呼叫利兰，请回答，完毕
Come on，guys。These crates aren't gonna unload themselves.
加油啊，各位，箱子可不会自己卸自己
Too many cars here。Out of my way.
车太多了，都给我让开
Professor Zedapp？
泽达普教授？
Here it is，Professor。You wanted to see this before we load it？
就是这个，教授，在装船之前你要看看吗？
Ah，yes。Very carefully.
啊，是的，千万小心
Oh，a TV camera.
噢，摄像机
- What does it actually do？- This camera is extremely dangerous.
- 它是用来做什么的？- 这个摄像机非常非常危险
What are you up to now，Professor？
你在忙活什么呢，教授？
This is valuable equipment。Make sure it is properly secured for the voyage.
这是贵重设备，在途中一定要小心保护
- You got it。- Hey，Professor Z！
- 没错 - 嗨，Z教授！
This is one of those British spies we told you about.
这是我跟你说过的英国间谍之一
Yeah！This one we caught sticking his bumper where it didn't belong.
哈！我们抓住他时，他正呆在不该他去的地方
Agent Leland Turbo.
探员利兰·超动力
It's Finn McMissile！
那是芬恩·麦导弹！
He's seen the camera！Kill him！
他看到了摄像机，干掉他！
All hands on deck！All hands on deck！
全体就位！全体就位！
Whoa！
哇！
Waargh！
啊啊啊啊啊！
What？
他要干什么？
Get to the boats！
上快艇！
- He's getting away！- Not for long！
- 他逃脱了！- 逃不掉的！
He's dead，Professor.
解决他了，教授
Wunderbar！
妙极了！
With Finn McMissile gone，who can stop us now？
芬恩·麦导弹一死，谁还妨碍得了我们？
Mater-Tow Mater，that's who is here to help you.
脱线，拖车脱线，时刻为您服务
- Hey，Otis！- Hey，Mater.
- 嘿，奥的斯！- 嘿，脱线
I… Oh，gosh。I'm so sorry.
我…老天，真不好意思
I thought I could make it this time，but…
我以为这次能行呢，可是…
Smooth like pudding，huh？
多么流畅啊，是吧？
Who am I kidding？I'll always be a lemon.
唉，我这是骗谁呢？我一直都是辆柠檬车
Well，dad-gum，you're leaking oil again。Must be your gaskets.
真够呛，你又漏油了，肯定是垫圈的问题
Hey，but look on the bright side.
嘿，不过从好的一面来说
This is your tenth tow this month，so it's on the house.
这是你本月第十次拖车服务，所以免费哦
You're the only one that's nice to lemons like me，Mater.
脱线，只有你对我这种破车这么好
Don't sweat it。Shoot，these things happen to everybody.
别灰心，哇塞，每辆车都会出状况的
- But you never leak oil。- Yeah，but I ain't perfect.
- 可你就从不漏油 - 那倒是，不过我也不是十全十美的
Don't tell nobody，but I think my rust is starting to show through.
你可别告诉别人，我觉得我锈得越来越明显了
Hey。Is Lightning McQueen back yet？
嘿，闪电麦坤回来了吗？
Not yet.
还没
He must be crazy excited about winning his fourth Piston Cup.
他赢了第四座活塞杯，一定开心坏了
Four！Wow！
第四座！哇！
Yeah，we're so dad-gum proud of him，
是的，我们都为他骄傲死了
but I wish he'd hurry up and get back，
不过我希望他赶快回来
'cause we got a whole summer's worth of best friend fun to make up for.
因为最好的朋友要在一起欢度整个夏天
Just me and…
只有我和…
McQueen！
麦坤！
- Whoa，whoa，whoa！- McQueen！
- 哇，哇，哇！- 麦坤！
- Mater！I'm in no hurry！- Hey，everybody。McQueen's back！
- 脱线！我不赶时间！- 嘿，大伙儿，麦坤回来啦！
- Aaah！- McQueen's back！
- 啊啊！- 麦坤回来啦！
- McQueen's back！McQueen's back！- Aaah！Oooh-hoo！Oooh-hah！
- 麦坤回来啦！麦坤回来啦！- 啊！哦哦！哈！
McQueen's back！
麦坤回来啦！
Oh，Lightning！Welcome home！
噢，闪电！欢迎回来！
- Good to have you back，honey！- Congratulations，man.
- 你回来真是太好了，宝贝！- 祝贺你，兄弟
Welcome home，soldier.
欢迎回家，战士
The place wasn't the same without you，son.
这地方没你就是不一样，孩子
What？Did he go somewhere？
什么？他到别处去了？
It's good to be home，everybody.
大家好，回家真好
- Mater！- McQueen！
- 脱线！- 麦坤！
Oooh！
噢！
Whoooa！
哇哇！
Hey，how far did you make it this time，Otis？
嘿，奥的斯，这次你走了多远？
- Halfway to the county line。- Ooh，not bad，man！
- 到边境线还有一半路程 - 哦，还不错嘛，伙计！
I know！I can't believe it either！
就是！我也不相信呢！
- McQueen！Welcome back！- Mater，it's so good to see you.
- 麦坤！欢迎你回来！- 脱线，见到你真好
You too，buddy.
你也是，哥们儿
Oh，man，you ain't going to believe the things I got planned for us！
兄弟，你肯定猜不到我有什么好点子！
These best friend greetings get longer every year！
这哥俩见面真是一年比一年亲热！
- You ready to have some serious fun？- I've got something to show you first.
- 想不想试试真正好玩的？- 我有东西要先给你看
Wow.
哇
I can't believe they renamed the Piston Cup
真难以置信，活塞杯上有新名字了
after our very own Doc Hudson.
你的名字就在哈德森医生的下面
I know Doc said these things were just old cups，
我知道医生说这些不过是些旧杯子
but to have someone else win it just didn't feel right，you know？
但被其他人赢走了感觉还是不好，对吧？
Doc would've been real proud of you。That's for sure.
医生真的为你感到骄傲，我能肯定
All right，pal。I've been waiting all summer for this.
好了，哥们儿，我整个夏天就在等这个
- What you got planned？- Ho-ho-ho！You sure you can handle it？
- 你有什么好点子？- 嗬嗬！你确定自己能搞得定？
Do you know who you're talking to？This is Lightning McQueen！
瞧你说的，我可是闪电麦坤！
I can handle anything.
没什么是我搞不定的
Er… Mater？
呃…脱线？
Just remember，your brakes ain't going to work on these！
记住，刹车在这上没用！
- Mater？- Relax.
- 脱线？- 放轻松
These train tracks ain't been used in years！
这些铁轨好多年没用过了！
Aaaah！
啊啊！
- Aaaah！- Faster，faster。Come on。Here we go！
- 啊啊！- 快点，再快点，加油，来吧！
Faster！
加油！
Ooh。Wow.
哦，哇
Yeah，I don't know。Do you think？
嗯，我不确定，你觉得呢？
This is going to be good！
我觉得会很好玩的！
Did you see that？
看见没？
Uh-oh。This ain't going to be good.
噢哦，这就不好玩了
Ha-ha！Boy，this was the best day ever！
哈哈！今天过得最开心了！
And my favorite souvenir，this new dent.
还留了个新凹痕，我最喜欢的纪念
- Boy，Mater，today was ah… - Shoot，that was nothing.
- 天，脱线，今天真是… - 哇塞，这不算什么
Wait till you see what I got planned for tonight！
晚上等着看我的新点子吧！
Mater，Mater，whoa！I was thinking of just a quiet dinner.
脱线，脱线，喔！我只想安安静静吃顿晚饭
That's exactly what I was thinkin'.
我也是这么想的
- No，I meant with Sally，Mater。- Even better！
- 不是，我指莎莉，脱线 - 那更好了！
You，me and Miss Sally goin' out for supper.
你，我和莎莉小姐，出去吃晚饭
Mater，I meant it would be just me and Sally.
脱线，我是说就我和莎莉
- Oh。- You know，just for tonight.
- 哦 - 你明白的，就今晚
- Oh… - We'll do whatever you want tomorrow.
- 哦… - 明天你想玩什么都可以
OK.
好吧
- Thanks for understanding。- Yeah，sure.
- 理解万岁 - 是啊，当然
- Y'all go on and have fun now。- All right，then.
- 那你们玩得开心点 - 好的
See you soon，amigo.
回头见，兄弟
Ah，this is so nice.
啊，这里可真美
I can't tell you how good it is to be here alone，
我们总算能独自呆着，感觉真好
just the two of us，finally.
只有我们两个
- You and me。- Ahem！Good evening.
- 你和我 - 嗯哼！晚上好
- Oh！- My name is Mater，
- 哦！- 我叫脱线
and I'll be your waiter.
是你们的服务生
Mater the waiter。That's funny right there.
脱线服务生，真好玩
Mater？You work here？
脱线？你在这儿上班？
Yeah，I work here。What'd you think？
是啊，我在这儿上班，不然你以为呢？
I snuck in here when nobody was lookin'…
我趁人不备偷偷溜进来
and pretended to be your waiter…
假扮成你们的服务生
so I could hang out with you？
就为了跟你们一起玩？
Oh，yeah。How ridiculous would that be？
哦，也是，那多可笑呀是吧？
Can I start you two lovebirds off with a couple of drinks？
你们两个小情侣要点饮料吗？
- Yes。I'll have my usual。- You know what？I'll have that，too.
- 好的，我就喝平常喝的 - 这样好不好？我也要那个
Uh… Right。Your usual.
呃…对，你常喝的
- Thanks，man。- Grazie，Guido.
- 多谢，伙计 - 谢谢，圭多
Guido，what's McQueen's usual？
圭多，麦坤常喝的是什么饮料？
How should I know？
我怎么知道？
- Perfect。Give me two of them。- Quiet！My program's on.
- 好极了，来两杯 - 安静！我的节目开始了
Tonight on the Mel Dorado Show…
今夜，来到梅尔·多拉真人秀的是…
His story gripped the world.
他的故事全球瞩目
Oil billionaire Miles Axlerod，
石油大亨，亿万富翁麦尔斯·艾克斯勒洛德
in an attempt to become the first car to circumnavigate the globe without GPS，
力图成为不使用GPS进行环球航行的第一车
ironically ran out of gas，and found himself trapped in the wild.
讽刺的是，他耗尽燃油，身陷荒野
Feared dead，he emerged 36 days later，
36天后从死亡边缘生还
running on a fuel he distilled himself from the natural elements！
依靠他从自然界中提取的燃料发动了自己
Since then，he's sold his oil fortune，
此后，他就卖掉了石油公司
converted himself from a gas-guzzler into an electric car
自己从油老虎摇身一变为电动车
and has devoted his life to finding a renewable，clean-burning fuel.
并献身于寻找可再生清洁燃料的事业
Now he claims to have done it with his allinol.
如今他宣称他的聚合油公司已经完成这一使命
And to show the world what his new super fuel can do
并向全世界展示他的超级燃料的威力
he's created a racing competition like no other，
他举办了一项史无前例的赛车锦标赛
inviting the greatest champions
邀请最伟大的冠军选手
to battle in the first ever World Grand Prix.
在首轮国际大奖赛中一争高下
Welcome，Sir Miles Axlerod.
热烈欢迎，麦尔斯·艾克斯勒洛德
Thank you，Mel。It is good to be here。Listen to me.
谢谢，梅尔，很高兴上节目，请听我说
Big oil。It costs a fortune。Pollution is getting worse.
大量使用石油，耗资巨大，加剧污染
I mean，it's a fossil fuel。「Fossil，」 as in dead dinosaurs.
它是化石燃料，什么叫化石？就像灭绝的恐龙
And we all know what happened to them.
我们都知道它们是怎么灭绝的
Alternative energy is the future。Trust me，Mel.
新能源是未来的趋势，相信我，梅尔
After seeing allinol in action at the World Grand Prix，
凡是看过聚合油在国际大奖赛上的表现的人
nobody will ever go back to gasoline again.
绝不会再回去用汽油了
What happened to the dinosaurs，now？
那恐龙到底是怎么灭绝的呢？
And on satellite，a World Grand Prix competitor
现在卫星连线一位大奖赛的参赛选手
and one of the fastest cars in the world，Francesco Bernoulli.
世界上最快的车之一，弗朗西斯科·伯努利
It is an honor，Signore Dorado，for you.
真荣幸，多拉先生，你真荣幸
Why not invite Lightning McQueen？
为什么没邀请闪电麦坤？
Of course we invited him，
当然邀请了
but apparently after his very long racing season
但显然，经过了这么长的赛季之后
he is taking time off to rest.
他想休息休息
The Lightning McQueen would not have a chance against Francesco.
闪电麦坤不会有机会赢弗朗西斯科的
I can go over 300 kilometers an hour.
我每小时可以跑300公里
In miles，that is like… way faster than McQueen.
换算成英里就是…总之比麦坤快多了
Let's go to the phones.
我们来进行电话连线
Baltimore，Maryland，you're on the air.
马里兰州巴尔的摩的听众，你的电话接通了
- Am I on？Hello？- You're on。Go ahead.
- 真的吗？你好？- 是的，请讲话
- Hello？- Go ahead.
- 你好？- 请说
Let's go to Radiator Springs.
我们来接通油车水镇的电话
You're on，caller.
这位听众，你已经打进来了
That Italian feller you got on there
你们弄来的那个意大利家伙
can't talk that way about Lightning McQueen.
不许这样乱讲闪电麦坤
He's the bestest race car in the whole wide world.
他是全世界跑得最快的车
- Uh- oh。- If he is，how you say，
- 噢哦 - 如果他是，用你的说法
「the bestest race car」，then why must he rest？Huh？
「跑得最快的车」，那他干嘛非要休息呢？
'Cause he knows what's important.
因为他知道什么是最重要的
Every now and then he prefers just to slow down，enjoy life.
他更喜欢时不时地放慢脚步，享受生活
Oh！You heard it！Lightning McQueen prefers to be slow！
噢！你们听见了！闪电麦坤更喜欢慢慢开！
This is not news to Francesco.
当然了，这对弗朗西斯来说不新鲜
When I want to go to sleep，I watch one of his races.
我想睡觉的时候就看他的比赛
After two laps，I am out cold.
跑完两圈之后，我就打瞌睡了
That ain't what I meant.
我不是那个意思
What's going on over there？
那边出什么事了？
He is afraid of Francesco.
他怕弗朗西斯科
That's that Italian formula car.
是那辆意大利方程式赛车
- His name is… - Francesco Bernoulli.
- 他叫… - 弗朗西斯科·伯努利
- No wonder there's a crowd。- Why do you know his name？
- 难怪都挤过来看 - 你怎么知道他名字？
And don't say it like that。It's three syllables，not ten.
别那么说话，好像大舌头似的
What？He's nice to look at.
什么嘛，他多帅呀
You know，open-wheeled and all.
开放式轮胎，浑身上下都有型
What's wrong with fenders？I thought you liked my fenders.
挡泥板不好吗？我还以为你喜欢我的挡泥板
- Let me tell you something else。- Mater？
- 我告诉你吧 - 脱线？
McQueen could drive circles around you.
麦坤能围着你转圈跑
Driving in circles is all he can-a do，no？
他就只会转圈跑啊，不是吧？
No.
当然不是
I mean，yes。I mean，he could beat you anywhere.
我是说，我是说，他不管在哪儿都能跑过你
Any time，any track.
不管什么时候，什么赛道
Mel，can we move on？
梅尔，我们能继续吗？
Francesco needs a caller who can provide
弗朗西斯科需要一位稍微聪明点的听众
a little more intellectual stimulation，like a dump truck.
比如一辆自卸卡车
Ha-ha！That shows what you know。Dump trucks is dumb.
哈哈！丢人了吧，自卸车都是哑巴
Hey！Whoa！
嘿！哇！
Yeah，hi。This is Lightning McQueen.
嗨，我是闪电麦坤
The Lightning McQueen，huh？
闪电麦坤？
I don't appreciate my best friend being insulted like that.
我不喜欢你那样侮辱我最好的朋友
McQueen，that was your best friend？Oh！
麦坤，那是你最好的朋友？哦！
This is the difference between you and Francesco.
这就是你和弗朗西斯科的不同之处了
Francesco knows how good he is.
弗朗西斯科知道自己有多棒
He does not need to surround himself with tow trucks to prove it.
他不需要拖车围在身边来证明这一点
Those are strong words from a car that is so fragile.
真是外强中干啊
Fragile！He calls Francesco fragile！
外强中干！他说弗朗西斯科外强中干！
Not-a so fast，McQueen！
你可不够快，麦坤！
「Not so fast。」 Is that your new motto？
「不够快」是你的新座右铭吗？
Motto？
座右铭？
This sounds like something that needs to be settled on the race course.
看起来这事得在赛场上解决了
What do you say，Lightning McQueen？
你看怎么样，闪电麦坤？
We've got room for one more racer.
我们还能再加一位选手
I would love to，but my crew is off for the season，so…
很乐意，不过我的团队已经休假了，所以…
（艾尔·雷欧·麦坤之队）
Pit stop.
「加油维修站」
You know what？They just got back.
不过呢，他们刚刚回来了
Deal me in，baby.
算我一个，兄弟们
Ka-chow！Yeah.
咔嚓！耶
I know，I know。I just got back，but we won't be long.
我知道我刚回来，不过我们不会去太久的
No，don't worry about me。I've got enough to do here.
别担心我，我在这儿有很多事做
Mater's going to have a blast，though.
不过脱线会玩得很开心的
You're bringing Mater，right？
你要带脱线去的吧？
You never bring him to any of your races.
你从来没带他参加过你的比赛
Ah.
啊
Just let him sit in the pits。Give him a headset.
就让他呆在维修站，给他戴个耳机
Come on，it will be the thrill of a lifetime for him.
答应嘛，这肯定会是他这辈子最兴奋的事了
- Your drink，sir。- Mater.
- 你的饮料，先生 - 脱线
I didn't taste it！
我没偷喝！
How'd you like to come and see the world with me？
想跟我来看看世界吗？
- You mean it？- Yeah。You got me into this thing.
- 你说真的？- 是啊，这事是你给我招来的
- You're coming along。- All right！
- 你也跑不了 - 太好了！
Ka-chow！
咔嚓！
Ha-ha！
哈哈！
Hey！
嘿！
Hey，excuse me！
嘿！借过！
Domo arigato！
我是多摩君，谢谢！
Yeah！
耶！
Guido，look。Ferraris and tires.
圭多，看呀，法拉利，还有轮胎
- Let's go！- Ho- ho！Look at this.
- 快来！- 嗬嗬！看这个
OK，now，Mater，remember，best behavior.
从现在起，脱线，要记住，要乖乖的
- You got it，buddy。Hey，what's that？- Mater！
- 听你的，哥们儿，嘿，那是什么？- 脱线！
Hey，McQueen！Over here.
嘿，麦坤！过来
- Lewis！- Hey，man.
- 路易斯！- 嗨，兄弟
- Jeff！- Hey，Lightning.
- 杰夫！- 嗨，闪电
Can you believe this party？
这个晚会真棒啊
Hey.
嗨
You done good。You got all the leaves.
你干得真不错，把叶子都清干净了
- Check out that tow truck。- Man，I wonder who that guy's with.
- 看那个拖车 - 不知道是跟谁一起来的
Ah… Will you guys excuse me just for one little second？
啊…不好意思，我离开一小会儿
Ho-ho！Good job！
嗬嗬！干得好！
Mater！Listen，this isn't Radiator Springs.
脱线！听着，这里不是油车水镇
You're just realizing that？
你才知道啊？
Oh-ho！That jet lag really done a number on you.
嗬嗬！你还没倒过时差来吧
Mater，things are different over here.
脱线，这里跟家里不一样
Which means maybe you should，you know，act a little different，too.
也就是说，你的举止也要跟在家时不一样
- Different than what？- Well，just help me out here.
- 怎么个不一样法？- 就当帮我忙
You need help？Shoot！Why didn't you say so？
你要帮忙？哇塞，干嘛这么客气
That's what a tow truck does.
咱拖车就是干这个的
- Yeah，I mean… - Looky there.
- 对，我是说… - 看那边
It's Mr。San Francisco。I'll introduce you.
是圣弗朗西斯科先生，我来介绍你
- Mater，no！- Look at me。I'm helping you already.
- 不要啊，脱线！- 看着我，我已经在帮你了
Hey，Mr。San Francisco，I'd like you to meet…
嗨，圣弗朗西斯科先生，我介绍你认识…
Ah，Lightning McQueen！Buona sera.
啊，闪电麦坤！晚上好
- Nice to meet you，Francesco。- Nice to meet you，too.
- 幸会，弗朗西斯科 - 幸会
You are very good-looking。Not as good as I thought，but good.
你看起来很帅，没我想得那么帅，但还不错
Excuse me。Can I get a picture with you？
不好意思，能合个影吗？
Anything for McQueen's friend.
麦坤的朋友就是我朋友
Miss Sally is going to flip when she sees this.
莎莉小姐看到这个会高兴得跳起来
She's Lightning McQueen's girlfriend.
她是闪电麦坤的女朋友
- Oooh！- She's a big fan of yours.
- 喔！- 她是你的狂热粉丝
Hey，she has a good taste.
嘿，她品味不错嘛
Mater's prone to exaggeration。I wouldn't say she's a 「big fan」.
脱线太夸张了，我不觉得她是「狂热粉丝」
You're right。She's a huge fan！
没错，她是超级狂热粉丝！
She goes on and on about your open wheels.
她没完没了地说你的开放式轮胎
Mentioning it once doesn't qualify as going on and on.
就提过一次，哪有没完没了
Francesco is familiar with this reaction to Francesco.
弗朗西斯科对粉丝的狂热早就习惯了
Women respect a car that has a nothing to hide.
女人热爱一辆车很正常，不需要掩饰
Yeah，er…
是啊，呃…
- Let us have a toast。- Let's.
- 我们干杯吧 - 我们？
I dedicate my win tomorrow to Miss Sally.
将我明日的胜利献给莎莉小姐
Oh。Sorry.
噢，不好意思
I already dedicated my win tomorrow to her.
我已经把我明日的胜利献给她了
So，if we both do it，it's really not so special.
要是我们都献就没意思了
- Besides，I don't have a drink。- I'll go get you one.
- 另外我也没有饮料 - 我去给你拿一杯
Do you mind if I borrow a few bucks for one of them drinks？
我能不能跟他们借几块钱买饮料啊？
- They're free。- Free？Shoot，what am I doing here？
- 饮料是免费的 - 免费？哇塞，那我还呆在这儿干什么？
I should probably go keep an eye on him。See you at the race.
我得看着他点儿，明天赛场上见
Yes，you will see Francesco，but not like this.
是的，你会见到弗朗西斯科的，但不是这样
You will see him like a this as he drives away from you.
而是这样，并且离你越来越远
Ha！That's cute.
哈，还挺可爱的
You had one of those made up for all the racers？
你给每辆参赛的车都画一个吗？
No.
不是
Okay.
那就好
- Ciao，McQueen！- He is so getting beat tomorrow！
- 拜拜，麦坤！- 明天他一定输得很惨！
Ladies and gentlecars，Sir Miles Axlerod.
女士们先生们，有请麦尔斯·艾克斯勒洛德
It is my absolute honor to introduce to you
我极其荣幸地向你们介绍
the competitors in the first ever World Grand Prix.
第一次国际赛车大奖赛的选手们
From Brazil，Number 8…
来自巴西的8号…
- Oh，hello。- Hello.
- 噢，你好 - 你好
A Volkswagen Karmann Ghia has no radiator.
为什么大众卡尔曼·吉亚没有散热器
That's because it's air cooled.
因为它采用风冷系统
Great。I'm Agent Shiftwell.
好极了，我是灵智速探员
Holley Shiftwell from the Tokyo station.
东京站的霍莉·灵智速
- I have a message from London。- Not here.
- 我有来自伦敦的情报 - 别在这儿说
Try the canap on the mezzanine
尝尝中楼的点心吧
The lab boys analyzed the photo I sent？
实验人员分析了我发的照片吗？
What did they learn about the camera？
关于摄像机有什么发现？
It appears to be a standard television camera.
看起来是一台标准的电视摄像机
They said if you could get closer photos next time that would be great.
他们说最好你下次能拍到距离更近的照片
This was London's message？
这就是伦敦的情报？
Oh，no。No，sir.
哦，不，长官
The oil platforms you were on，
你看到的那个钻井平台
turns out they're sitting on the biggest oil reserve in the world.
位于世界储油量最大的油田上
How did we miss that？
我们怎么会没发现它呢？
They've scrambled everyone's satellites.
他们对所有的卫星都实施了干扰
The Americans discovered it just before you did.
美国人在你之前刚刚发现它
They placed an agent on that platform under deep cover.
他们在那里安插了一位隐藏很深的卧底探员
He was able to get a photo of the car
他能弄到那辆车的照片
who's running the entire operation.
我们就知道是谁在背后操控一切了
Great.
很好
Who is it？Has anyone seen the photo yet？
是哪辆车？有人见过照片吗？
Nope，not yet.
不，还没有
The American is here tonight to pass it to you.
今晚美国人来这里把照片交给你
He'll signal you when he's ready.
他准备好后会给你发信号
Good，good.
很好，很好
Oh，no.
哦，不
- What is it？- Change of plan.
- 怎么了？- 计划有变
- You're meeting the American。- What？Me？
- 你去见美国人 - 什么？我？
Those thugs down there were on the oil platform.
下面那些恶棍就是钻井平台上的
If they see me，the mission is compromised.
让他们看见我，行动会暴露的
No，I'm technical。I'm in diagnostics.
可我是技术员，我是在实验室做分析的
I'm… I'm not a field agent
我…我不是外勤探员
You are now.
现在是了
I'll take one of them。Thank you.
给我来一个，谢谢
Never know which one McQueen will have a hankering for.
老是搞不清麦坤喜欢喝哪一种
Hey。What you got here that's free？
嗨，你这儿有什么是免费的？
How about that pistachio ice cream？
那个开心果冰激凌免费吗？
- No，no，wasabi。- Same old same old.
- 不，这是芥末酱 - 差不多啦差不多啦
What's up with you？That looks delicious！
怎么了？这东西看上去很好吃的样子啊！
Er… little more，please。It is free，right？
呃…请再来点，不是免费的吗？
Keep it coming。A little more.
继续继续，再多来点
Come on，let's go。It's free.
来嘛，别舍不得，免费的嘛
You're gettin' there。Scoop，scoop.
就这样，来一勺，一大勺
There ya go！Now that's a scoop of ice cream！
这就对了嘛，一大勺冰激凌！
My condolences.
深表同情
And now our last competitor.
现在出场的是我们最后一位选手
Number 95，Lightning McQueen！
95号，闪电麦坤！
Ka-chow！
咔嚓！
Thank you so much for having us，Sir Axlerod.
非常感谢您的邀请，艾克斯勒洛德先生
I really look forward to racing。This is a great opportunity.
我很期待参加比赛，这是个很好的机会
Oh，the pleasure is all ours，Lightning.
噢，大家都很高兴，闪电
You and your team bring excellence and professionalism
你和你的团队为比赛
to this competition.
带来了卓越和专业的精神
Somebody get me water！Aah！
谁能给我点水！啊！
Oh，sweet relief。Sweet relief.
哦，凉快多了，凉快多了
Whatever you do，do not eat the free pistachio ice cream.
无论如何，不要吃免费的开心果冰激凌
It has turned.
它变质啦
Sir Axlerod，I can explain.
艾克斯勒洛德先生，很抱歉
- This is Mater。He's… - I know him.
- 这是脱线，他… - 我认识他
This is the bloke that called in to the television show.
就是那个把电话打进节目的家伙嘛
- You're the one I have to thank。- No，thank you.
- 我得谢谢你 - 不，谢谢你
This trip's been amazin'.
这次旅行太棒了
Ah。He's a little excited，isn't he？
哈，他有点兴奋，是吧？
- Mater！- But wait，I… Oh，shoot.
- 脱线！- 等等，我…哦，哇塞
- Mater。- Has anyone got a towel？
- 脱线 - 谁有毛巾？
Mater，get a hold of yourself。You're making a scene！
脱线，控制一下你自己，别出丑了
- But I never leak oil。Never。- Go take care of yourself right now！
- 可我从来不漏油的，从来不漏 - 马上去拾掇一下自己！
Comin' through！Leakin' oil。Where's the bathroom？Thank you.
请让让！漏油了，卫生间在哪儿？谢谢
I gotta go。Oh，er…
我得马上，哦，呃…
Er…
呃…
Sorry，ladies.
抱歉，女士们
I'm leakin'。I never leak。I never leak.
居然漏油，我从来不漏油的
I never leak，I never leak，I never leak.
从来不漏油，从来不，从来不
Oh，oh，I never leak。Oooh！
哦，我从来不漏油，唔！
I never leak，I never leak，never…
从来不漏油，从来不，从来…
Wow-wee！
哇噢！
What in the？
里面是？
Hey，that tickles！
嘿，好痒啊！
Waaargh！
哇哇哇！
Okay，McMissile。I'm here。It's time for the drop.
麦导弹，我到了，是时候放货了
OK，so，the American has activated his tracking beacon.
好的，美国人激活了他的跟踪信号
Roger that。Move in.
收到，跟进
Stop！Hey！
停下！嘿！
- Oh，you've got to be joking。- What's the problem？
- 哦，开什么玩笑 - 怎么了？
- He's in the loo。- So，go in！
- 他在洗手间 - 那就进去
- I can't go into the men's loo！- Time is of the essence.
- 我不能进男厕所！- 时间紧急
All right.
好吧
Oh！Whatever you do，I would not go in there！
噢！不管怎么着，我是再也不进去了！
Hey！A Gremlin and a Pacer！
嗨，格里莫林和步行者！
No offense to your makes and models，
不是说你们的品牌和型号不好
but you break down harder than my cousin Betsy
不过比起我那个被闲置不用的表妹贝茜
after she got left at the altar！
你们出故障更严重
What the？Whoa。Are you OK？
搞什…？哇，你还好吧？
- I'm fine。- Hey！Tow truck！
- 我没事 - 嘿，拖车！
We'd like to get to our private business here，if you don't mind.
我们要谈点私事，你不介意回避下吧
Oh，yeah，sorry.
噢，抱歉
Don't let me get in the way of your private business.
别让我妨碍了你们谈私事
Oh，a little advice.
还有点小忠告
When you hear a giggle and see that waterfall，
当你们听见咯咯笑声，看见瀑布的时候
you best press that green button.
最好按绿色按钮
- Thank you。- It's to adjust the temperature.
- 多谢 - 它是用来调节温度的
- Got it。- And it's in Celsius，not Fahrenheit.
- 知道了 - 是摄氏度，不是华氏度
Get out of here！
马上消失！
All right，then。And when she starts gigglin'，
好好，等她开始咯咯笑的时候
prepare to be squirted.
你们就准备被喷吧
'Scuse me，ma'am.
抱歉，女士
Dad gum pistachio ice cream.
该死的开心果冰激凌
This cannot be him。Is he American？
不会是他吧？他是美国人吗？
Look out，ladies。Mater's fittin' to get funky.
当心了女士们，脱线要耍帅了
- Extremely。- Then it's him.
- 太像美国人了 - 那就是他
- Hello。- Well，hello.
- 你好 - 你好
A Volkswagen Karmann Ghia has no radiator.
为什么大众卡尔曼·吉亚没有散热器
Well，of course it doesn't。That's 'cause it's air- cooled.
当然不需要，因为它采用风冷系统
Perfect。Erm… I'm from the Tokyo Station.
好极了，嗯…我是东京站的
'Course，Karmann Ghias weren't the only ones.
当然了，卡尔曼·吉亚不是唯一的一款
Besides the Beetles，you had Type 3 Squarebacks with the Pancake motors.
还有甲壳虫，3型方背式车身，盘式电动机
- Yeah，OK。I get it。- And before both of them
- 是的，我知道 - 而且在他们之前
there's the Type 2 buses.
还有2型客车
- My buddy Fillmore's one of them。- Listen！
- 我朋友菲尔莫就是一个 - 听着！
Erm… We should find somewhere more private.
嗯…我们应该找个更隐蔽的地方
Gee，don't you think that's a little？
老天，你觉得有这样的地方吗？
You're right。Impossible to know which areas here are compromised.
也对，没法知道哪个地方已经暴露了
- So，when can I see you again？- Well，let's see.
- 那么，我能再见到你吧？- 让我想想
- Tomorrow I'll be out there at the races。- Got it.
- 明天，我会去赛场 - 明白
We'll rendezvous then.
那我们就在那儿会合
- There you are。Where have you been？- What's a 「rendezvous」？
- 你回来了，刚才去哪儿了？- 「会合」是什么意思？
- Er… It's like a date。- A date？
- 呃…有点像约会 - 约会？
Mater，what's going on？
脱线，出什么事了？
What's going on is I got me a date tomorrow.
出的事就是明天我有个约会
Guido don't believe you.
圭多表示不相信
Believe it。My new girlfriend just said so.
相信吧，我的新女友刚才说的
Hey，there she is。Hey！Hey，lady！
嘿，她在哪儿呢，嗨！女士！
See you tomorrow！
明儿见！
Guido still don't believe you.
圭多表示依然不相信
- I got to admit，you tricked us real good。- And we don't like being tricked.
- 我得承认，你把我们耍得团团转 - 我们不喜欢被人耍
What's so funny？
有什么好笑的？
Well，I was just wearing a disguise.
刚才我穿了一身很丑的伪装
You guys are stuck looking like that.
跟你们看起来很像
Allinol？Thanks，fellas.
聚合油？谢了，伙计
I hear this stuff is good for you.
我听说他们的东西不错
So you think.
你这么想的？
Allinol by itself is good for you.
聚合油本身是不错
But after microscopic examination
不过经过深入研究
I have found that it has one small weakness.
我发现它有一个小缺陷
When hit with an electromagnetic pulse，
当受到电磁脉冲冲击的时候
it becomes extremely dangerous.
它会变得极度危险
Smile for the camera.
来笑一个
Is that all you want？I got a whole act.
你要拍电影吗？我全程出演
You were very interested
你在钻井平台上的时候
in this camera on the oil platform.
对这个摄像机非常感兴趣
Now，you will witness what it really does.
现在你可以亲眼目睹它的真正作用了
- Whatever you say，Professor。- You talked up a lot of cars last night.
- 随你怎么说，教授 - 你昨晚跟很多车说过话
- Which one's your associate？- Your mother.
- 哪一辆是你的同伙？- 你妈妈
Oh，no，I'm sorry，it was your sister.
哦，不，我错了，是你妹妹
I can't tell them apart these days.
我一直分不清她们
Could I start it now，Professor Z？
能开始了吗，Z教授？
Go 50？power.
加到50%动力值
This camera is actually an electromagnetic pulse emitter.
这个摄像机实际上是电磁脉冲发射器
What about her？Did you give it to her？
是她吗？你交给她了吗？
The allinol is now heating to a boil，
聚合油现在快要沸腾了
dramatically expanding，causing the engine block to crack under the stress，
会急剧膨胀，导致气缸在压力下爆裂
forcing oil into the combustion chamber.
把油压迫进燃烧室
How about him？Did you talk to him？
是他吗？你跟他说过话吗？
What do I care？I can replace an engine block.
那又怎样，我可以换一个气缸
You may be able to，but after full impact of the pulse…
也许吧，不过如果脉冲波开到最大
unfortunately… there will be nothing to replace.
很不幸，就什么也没法修了
How about him？Does he have it？
他呢？给他了吗？
That's him。He's the one.
是他，就是他了
- Roger that，Professor Z。- No！
- 收到，Z教授 - 不要！
Yes，sir.
是的，先生
We believe the infiltrator has passed along sensitive information.
我们相信卧底送出了一些高度机密信息
I will take care of it before any damage can be done.
在造成严重后果之前我会解决的
The project is still on schedule.
行动按原计划执行
You will find the second agent and kill him.
你们去找另外那个探员，干掉他
Japan，land of the rising sun，
日本，旭日之国
where ancient tradition meets modern technology.
古代传统与现代科技在此相遇
Welcome to the inaugural running of the World Grand Prix.
欢迎收看世界赛车大奖赛的现场报道
I'm Brent Mustangburger
我是布伦特·马斯唐伯格
with racing legends
在我身边的是两位传奇人物
Darrell Cartrip and David Hobbscap.
达雷尔·卡特里普和大卫·霍布斯卡普
There's never been a competition like this before.
这是一场前所未有的赛事
First，allinol，making its debut tonight
首先，聚合油作为所有大型比赛的指定燃料
as the required fuel for all these great champions.
将于今晚首次亮相
Second，the course itself.
其次是赛道
And it's like nothing we've ever seen before.
也是我们前所未见的
David，how exactly does this competition work？
大卫，这次比赛的规则究竟是什么样的呢？
All three of these street courses are classic round the house racetracks.
三条赛道都是经典的环形跑道
This means that the LMP and formula cars
这意味着兰博基尼概念赛车和方程式赛车
should break out of the gate in spectacular fashion.
将以最华丽的姿态冲出起跑线
Look for Francesco Bernoulli，in particular，to lead early.
特别是弗朗西斯科·伯努利有望占据领先地位
And with technical turns throughout，
而高性能跑车和巡回车
GT and touring cars，
在所有的弯道处都可以扳回局面
like Spain's Miguel Camino，should make up ground
比如西班牙的米格尔·卡米诺
but I doubt it'll be enough to stop Francesco
但我怀疑仍不足以赶超弗朗西斯科
from absolutely running away with it.
因为他拥有绝对优势
Whoa now。Hold your horsepower.
哦，呵呵，言之过早了
You forget the most important factor.
你遗漏了一个重要因素
that early dirt track section of the course.
就是赛道前方的土路部分
The dirt is supposed to be the equalizer in this race.
在这场比赛中土路被用来平衡速度
French rally car Raoul Roule
法国拉力赛车拉乌尔·撒儒勒
is counting on a big boost through there.
就期待在土路段提升速度
And don't forget Lightning McQueen.
还有别忘了闪电麦坤
His mentor，the Hudson Hornet，
他的教练，大黄蜂哈德森
was one of the greatest dirt track racers of all time.
一直是最厉害的土路赛车手
In my opinion，McQueen is the best all around racer in this competition.
在我看来，麦坤是这次比赛中最全面的选手
Really，Darrell，
说真的，达雷尔
you need to clean your windshield.
你应该擦一下你的挡风玻璃了
You're clearly not seeing this for what it is：
有一点你显然没看清：
Francesco's race to lose.
弗朗西斯科从没输过比赛
It's time to find out。The racers are locking into the grid.
是时候揭晓疑问了，参赛者已经就位
Speed。I am speed.
速度，我就是速度
Really？You are speed？
真的吗？你就是速度？
Then Francesco is triple speed.
那弗朗西斯科就是三倍速度
Francesco is triple speed.
弗朗西斯科是三倍速度
Ho-ho！Francesco likes a this McQueen.
嗬嗬！弗朗西斯科喜欢麦坤
It's a really getting him into the zone.
但愿他别落得太远
He is so getting beat today.
今天我要他好看
- Your suspension sets look good。- Tire pressure is excellent！
- 你的悬架不错 - 胎压很正常！
- He's got plenty of fuel。- And he's awesome.
- 他燃料充足 - 他帅呆了
- Why is he in the pits？He's so exposed。- It's his cover.
- 他怎么在维修站？太容易暴露了 - 那是伪装
One of the best I've seen，too。Look at the detail on that rust.
也是我见过的最好的伪装，瞧那些锈斑的细节
It must have cost him a fortune.
肯定花了他一大笔钱
- But why hasn't he contacted us yet？- There's probably heat on him.
- 可他怎么还不联系我们 - 可能他不方便
- Be patient。- Right，of course.
- 要有耐心 - 好的，一定
- He'll signal us when he can。- Then we find out who's behind all this.
- 时机到了他会给我们发信号 - 那就能找出幕后黑手了
As they head into the palace hairpin，Francesco builds an early lead.
他们进入了第一个U形弯道，弗朗西斯科领先
Hang on，boys。Here comes the dirt.
坚持住，小伙子们，就要进入土路了
Slipping and sliding，baby.
飘移再加侧滑，宝贝
McQueen，it's time to make your move！
麦坤，你的机会来了！
Get on the outside and show 'im what Doc taught you.
上外圈，把医生教你的本事拿出来
10-4，Mater.
知道了，脱线
Oh，boy！Francesco's brought to a screeching halt！
哦天哪！弗朗西斯科来了个急刹车！
Lightning McQueen is the first to take advantage.
闪电麦坤第一个把握住时机
And just like that，folks，Francesco's lead is left in the dust.
观众们，弗朗西斯科在土路上失去了领先地位
Nice call，Mater。Keep it up.
好主意，脱线，继续哦
Whoo-hoo！
噢嗬！
McQueen looks happier than a roll bar at a demolition derby！
麦坤看上去比德贝冲撞赛上的保护杆还开心
Everyone's jostling for position as we hit the asphalt again.
回到柏油路面之后每辆车都在争抢位置
Francesco lost a lot of momentum in the dirt.
弗朗西斯科在土路上势头大减
He's got serious work ahead of him if he wants to get back in this race.
他要想重回首位需要加倍努力
The racers hit the Rainbow Bridge，with its 360-degree loop.
选手们到达了彩虹桥，这里是360度的弯道
- It is time。- Roger that.
- 是时候了 - 收到
Oh！Miguel Camino has blown an engine！
噢！米格尔·卡米诺气缸爆了！
Very unusual，Darrell。He's been so consistent all year.
很奇怪，达雷尔，他今年一直发挥稳定
- You gotta be kidding me。- What is it？
- 开什么玩笑 - 怎么了？
- The tow truck from the bathroom。- The bathroom？
- 厕所里那个拖车 - 厕所里的拖车？
The one the American agent passed the device to.
美国特工把设备交给他了
- What about him？- He's in the pits！
- 他怎么了？- 他在维修站！
Not for long.
他呆不久了
- Hold on。I think I've got something。- What is it？
- 等等，我有发现 - 什么？
The Pacer from the party last night.
昨晚晚会上的那辆步行者
I'm cross referencing with the photos from the oil derricks.
我来和钻井台的照片做个比对
Yep。His VIN numbers match.
没错，他的车辆识别号是匹配的
Anyone with him？He won't be alone.
有人和他一起吗？他不可能单独行动
Conducting analysis on the target。He's not the only one here.
进行目标分析，他不是单独行动的
Three，five… They're everywhere。And they're all closing in on…
三辆，五辆…到处都是，他们正在接近…
Oh，no！Finn？Finn，where are you？
哦不！芬恩？芬恩，你在哪儿？
Get him out of the pits。Now！
让他离开维修站，快！
Wow！Some of them fellers is really loud！
哇噢！有些家伙真能嚷嚷啊！
- Can you hear me？Over。- What？
- 能听见吗？完毕 - 什么？
Get out of the pit now！Do you hear me？
马上离开维修站！听见了吗？
Hey。I know you！You're that girl from the party last night.
嘿，我认识你！你是昨天晚会上的姑娘
You wanna do our date now？
你想现在就约会吗？
Guys，too much chatter。Let's keep this line clear.
哥们儿，别闲聊了，线路要保持畅通
Smoke from number 10，Clutchgoneski！
10号冒烟了，克拉奇冈斯基！
Ha-ha-ha！
哈哈哈！
There's no time for messing about！Get out of the pits！
没时间胡闹了，离开维修站！
Is there going to be cable where you is so I can watch the rest of the race？
我们要去的地方有信号吗？我还想继续看比赛
- You're running out of time！- They're coming。Get him out of there！
- 没时间了！- 他们来了，把他弄走！
I'm trying。Get out now.
我在想办法呢，现在就出去
I usually like to have a proper detailin' done before I meet a lady friend.
我通常在见女性朋友之前喜欢正式打扮一下
Huh？
嗯？
- Finn McMissile！But you're dead！- Then this shouldn't hurt.
- 芬恩·麦导弹！你不是死了吗？- 那现在就不会伤心了
Miss Shiftwell？
灵智速小姐？
I've got him in the back alleys east of the garages.
我让他去车库东边的后巷
Multiple assailants are closing in quickly.
众多攻击者正迅速接近
Keep him moving。I'm on my way.
让他一直开，我这就过来
Hey，new lady friend，you like flowers？
嘿，姑娘，你喜欢花吗？
What？
什么？
No！Don't go in anywhere。Just keep moving.
不！哪儿也别去，一直开
- Stay outside。Got you。- Outside？
- 呆在外面，我来啦 - 外面？
Whoa！McQueen suddenly moves to the outside.
哇噢！麦坤突然跑到外圈
I cannot believe what I saw.
简直难以置信
That was a bonehead move to open up the inside like that！
这样做太愚蠢了，就这么让开了内道！
That might have cost McQueen the victory！
这可能会使麦坤丢掉冠军！
This time，I'm going to make sure you stay dead！
这次我要确保你必死无疑！
You're doing brilliantly。Now just stay focused.
你做得很好，保持注意力集中
What's that？You want me to head toward that ruckus？
那是怎么回事？要我去看看那边吵什么吗？
No！Don't go down that street.
不要！别到那条街上去
Ohh！
噢！
Hi-yah！
嗨，呀！
Wow！A live karate demonstration！
哇噢！空手道表演！
Stop it，Mater。Just sign off.
住嘴，脱线，关掉广播
Aaargh！
啊！
And here they come，the two leaders.
两位选手在争夺领先位置
Bumper to bumper as they approach the finish line！
他们接近终点线了！保险杠挨着保险杠！
- It's close！- Francesco's the winner！
- 胜利在望！- 弗朗西斯科获胜！
McQueen's number two.
麦坤获得亚军
That was cool！Can I get your autograph？
真酷！能给我签个名吗？
Where'd he go？
他去哪儿了？
Our rendezvous has been jeopardized。Keep the device safe.
我们见面很危险，请保证设备安全
- We'll be in touch。- Dad- gum，did I miss our date？
- 我们保持联系 - 哎呀，我错过约会了吗？
- Francesco！- Francesco，over here.
- 弗朗西斯科！- 弗朗西斯科，看这边
What was your strategy today？
你今天采取的是什么战术？
Strategia？Francesco needs a no strategy.
战术？弗朗西斯科不需要战术
It's a very simple.
太简单了
You start the race，wait for Lightning McQueen to choke，pass him，then win.
起跑，等着麦坤熄火，超过他，然后就赢了
Francesco always- a wins。It's- a boring.
弗朗西斯科总是赢，真不好玩
You were in trouble for a while.
你状态不好有一阵子了
That dirt track section had you crawling.
土路那段赛道你简直是爬过去的
To truly crush one's dream，you must first raise their hopes very high.
要真正粉碎一个人的梦想
你必须先让他产生很高的期望
- Mater！- Hey，McQueen！What happened？
- 脱线！- 嘿，麦坤！怎么了？
Is the race over？You won，right？
比赛结束了？你赢了吧？
Why were you yelling at me while I was racing？
你在我比赛的时候瞎嚷嚷什么？
Yelling？Oh，you thought… That's funny right there.
瞎嚷嚷？哦，你以为…真有意思
No，that's 'cause I seen these two fellers doing
不是的，因为我看见两个家伙
some karate street performance.
在街头做空手道表演
It was nutso。One of 'em even had a flame thrower.
都玩疯了，其中一个居然还拿着喷火器
A flame thrower？What are you talking about？
喷火器？你在说什么？
- I don't understand。Where were you？- Going to meet my date.
- 我搞不懂，你去哪儿了？- 去赴约啊
Your date？
赴约？
She started talkin' to me as a voice in my head，
她跟我说话，告诉我到哪儿去
tellin' me where to go.
声音好像就在我脑子里
- What？- Wait a minute.
- 什么？- 等一下
- I didn't screw ya up，did I？- I lost the race because of you！
- 我没给你添乱吧？- 我输了比赛，就因为你！
Oh。I'm sorry。I didn't mean to.
哦，对不起，我不是故意的
An imaginary girlfriend？Flame throwers？
想象出来的女朋友？喷火器？
This is exactly why I don't bring you along to these things.
这就是为什么我不带你到这种场合来
Maybe if I，I don't know，
也许如果我…我也不知道了
talk to somebody and explained what happened，I could help.
跟什么人说说，解释一下，这个我能帮忙
I don't need your help！I don't want your help！
我不需要你帮忙！我不想要你帮忙！
Hey，there he is！
嘿，他在那儿！
- McQueen，you had it in the bag！- Yeah！What happened？
- 麦坤，冠军本来已经是你的了！- 是啊！怎么回事？
I made a mistake.
我犯了个错误
But I can assure you，it won't happen again.
但我向你们保证，以后不会再犯了
Look，we know what the problem is and we've taken care of it.
我们知道问题出在哪儿，我们会解决的
Lightning McQueen loses in the last lap to Francesco Bernoulli
在第一届世界赛车大奖赛中
in the first race of the World Grand Prix.
闪电麦坤在最后一圈输给了弗朗西斯科·伯努利
And three count 'em three cars flamed out
并且有三辆车，就是这三辆，燃烧熄火
leaving some to suggest that their fuel，allinol，might be to blame.
有暗示说他们的燃料聚合油应该承担责任
Allinol is safe。Alternative fuel is safe.
聚合油是安全的，可替代燃料是安全的
There is no way my fuel caused these cars to flame out.
我的燃料不可能造成这些车燃烧熄火
The jury may still be out on whether allinol caused these accidents，
评审团也许还没有得出结论说聚合油引发了事故
but one thing's for sure，
但有一件事确定无疑
Lightning McQueen blew this race.
闪电麦坤输掉了比赛
Team McQueen can't be happy right now.
麦坤团队现在一定心情沉重
Welcome to Tokyo International Airport.
欢迎来到东京国际机场
- Come with me，please，sir。- But I'm 'onna miss my plane.
- 请跟我来，先生 - 可我要误飞机了
- Right this way。- Ah，doggone it.
- 这边走 - 啊，怎么回事
This is about my hook，ain't it？
是因为我的钩子吧？
I know I should have checked it，but I can't，really.
我就知道应该先检查一下，但我真没办法
Look。It's attached to me.
看，它是固定的
Hey，I know you。You're that feller from the karate demonstration.
嘿，我认识你，你就是那个表演空手道的
I never properly introduced myself.
我还没正式自我介绍
Finn McMissile。British Intelligence.
芬恩·麦导弹，英国情报局
Tow Mater。Average intelligence.
拖车脱线，普通智商
Who are you with？FBI？CIA？
你在哪个机构工作？联邦调查局？中情局？
Let's just say I'm AAA affiliated.
就当我是美国汽车协会的吧
I know some karate.
我也会一些空手道
I don't want to brag or nuttin'，but I got me a black fan belt.
我不是吹牛或者炫耀，不过我是黑带哦
- Wanna see some moves I made up？- You're being followed.
- 想看看我自己编的动作吗？- 你被跟踪了
This first one，I can reach into a car's hood
第一个动作，打开一辆车发动机罩
pull out his battery，and show it to him before he stalls.
拔出电池，在他熄火之前给他看
I call it，「What I accidentally did to my friend Luigi once。」
我称之为「跟我的朋友路易吉开的一次玩笑」
Hey！Hi-yah-pah！
嘿！嗨呀啪！
- Hi-yah！- There he is！
- 嘿呀！- 他在那边！
Hi-hi-tah！Huh！
嗨嗨哒嗬！
Look，I probably ought to go。I'm about to miss my flight.
我说，我得走了，航班要误了
- Don't worry。I've taken care of that。- Whoa！
- 别担心，交给我了 - 哇！
Hang on！
稳住！
Whoa-hah-hah！
哇哈哈哈！
This is first class service.
这是头等舱服务
You don't even have to go through the terminal！
都不用走客运站！
Your karate partners is back there.
你的空手道搭档回来了
They look like they tryin' to catch up！
他们看起来很赶时间啊！
Drive forward。Whatever you do，don't stop！
只管开，无论如何别停！
- Whoa！- Whoa！
- 哇！- 哇！
Whoa…
哇哇哇
Is everything okay back there？
后面还好吧？
Finn，it's Sid。I'm on approach.
芬恩，我是西德，我快到了
Roger that.
收到
'Member that whole thing about me not stoppin' no matter what？
是你告诉我无论如何不要停下的哦
I knew I shoulda done carry on！
我就知道行李应该随身带！
Thanks，old boy.
谢谢，老朋友
- You got it，mate。- Hey，doggonit！
- 没问题，伙计 - 嘿，别挡路
Look，it's my imaginary girlfriend！
这不是我想象出来的女朋友嘛！
Come on！Get in here！
快，进来！
I tell you what，you really do want this first date，don't ya？
你对第一次约会真看重呀
That's a no quit attitude right there.
真是永不放弃，精神可嘉
What the？
怎么搞…？
- Aargh！- Hold on，Sid.
- 啊！- 坚持住，西德
Aargh！
啊！
Come on，Finn！It's now or never！
快，芬恩！再不上就来不及了！
Hold on！
坐稳了！
By the time you read this，
在你读到这封信的时候
I will be safely on an airplane flying home.
我已经平安登上回家的飞机了
By the time you read this，
在你读到这封信的时候
I will be safely on an airplane flying home.
我已经平安登上回家的飞机了
I'm so sorry for what I did.
很抱歉我做错了事
「I don't want to be the cause of you losing any more races.
「我不想让你再输掉更多的比赛了」
「I want you to go prove to the world what I already know.
「我要向世界证明我所知道的」
「That you are the greatest race car in the whole wide world.
「你才是全世界跑得最快的车」
「Your best friend，Mater。」
「你最好的朋友，脱线」
I didn't really want him to leave.
我没想真让他离开的
Wait，there's more here.
等等，还有几页
「PS。Please tell the hotel
「另：请告诉宾馆」
「I didn't mean to order that movie.
「我不是真的想订那部电影看」
「I thought it was just a preview and I didn't realize I was paying for it.
「我以为只是预告片，没想到要花钱的」
「PPS。That's funny right there。PP.」
「再另：玩得很开心」
There are a few more pages of PS's here.
还有好几页的「另」
Well，at least I know if he's at home，he'll be safe.
算了，至少我们知道他在家，平安无事
That's how I like to start the day.
我喜欢这样开始每一天
You never feel more alive than when you're almost dead.
只有在面对死亡的时候才会感觉充满生机
Yeah。I hope that device didn't fall off.
是啊，但愿设备没有掉下来
Whoa！
哇！
That's the closest I ever been to missin' my flight.
这是我赶航班最千钧一发的一次了
That was… Oh！
真是…哦！
- Still in one piece？Great。- I've got to go to a doctor.
- 毫发无损？好极了 - 我得去看医生
I get these sharp pains in my undercarriage.
我的底盘疼得要命
- Downloading the photo now。- Let me introduce you two.
- 正在下载照片 - 我来给你们两个介绍
This here is Finn McSomethin' or other.
这位是叫芬恩·麦什么的
He's a first class VIP airport whatchamacallit.
机场的头等贵宾什么的
And，Finn，this here is my date.
这位呢，芬恩，是我的约会对象
I never did get your name.
我一直不知道你名字
Oh，yes，sorry。It's Shiftwell。Holley Shiftwell.
哦，抱歉，我是灵智速，霍莉·灵智速
It's Shiftwell。Holley…
是灵智速，霍莉…
Finally。Time to see who's behind all this.
总算可以看到幕后黑手了
What is this？
这是什么？
That's one of the worst engines ever made.
这是世上最差劲的引擎之一
It's an old aluminum V8 with a Lucas electrical system
旧的铝制V型8缸，卢卡斯电力系统
and Whitworth bolts.
惠特沃斯螺栓
Shoot，them Whitworth bolts is a pain，tell you what.
哇塞，惠特沃斯螺栓最麻烦了，为什么呢
Them ain't metric，they ain't inches.
它们的长度单位既不是米，也不是英寸
Yes，OK，but whose engine is this？
行了，知道了，不过这是谁的引擎呢？
It's kinda hard to tell from this picture，ain't it？
从照片上很难看出来，对吧？
- But you took it。- Holley.
- 可这是你拍的 - 霍莉
Oh。Right！Yes，of course.
哦，是啊，当然了
A good agent gets what he can，
一个好探员要尽其所能弄到情报
then gets out before he's killed.
还要在被干掉之前脱身
Agent？You mean，like，insurance agent？Like…
代理？你是指保险代理这种？
Like a good neighbor，Mater is there！
远亲不如近邻，有麻烦找脱线
Wait！You mean secret agents！You guys is spies！
等等！你说的是秘密特工！你们是侦探！
In how many makes and models did this type of engine appear？
能在多少品牌和型号里找到这款引擎？
It was standard in seven models over a 12 year period.
它符合7个型号，12年以上的使用期
At least 35，000 cars were made with this engine.
至少有35，000辆车使用这款引擎
- You're purty。- Yes，thank you.
- 你真美 - 谢了
- And so nice。- Just pay attention.
- 人又这么好 - 专心点
This seems like a dead end.
看起来走到死胡同了
If there was something in the photo that could narrow this down，
要是照片里有什么东西能缩小调查范围
I'd be happier.
我会开心一点的
You might not be happy，but I bet this feller is.
你可能不会开心，不过我打赌这家伙会
See how he's had most of his parts replaced？
看到没，他把大部分零件都换掉了？
And see all them boxes over there？
看到旁边这些盒子了吗？
Them's all original parts。They ain't easy to come by.
都是原件，不容易买到的
- Rare parts？- That's something we can track.
- 稀缺零件？- 我们可以追踪这个
Exactly.
没错
Well done，Mater。I would never have seen that.
干得好，脱线，我就不会注意到那些
I know of a black market parts dealer in Paris，a treacherous lowlife，
我认识巴黎的一个黑市零件商，一个奸诈小人
but he's the only car in the world who can tell us whose engine this is.
不过他是唯一能告诉我们这些引擎来源的车了
What would you say to setting up an informal task force on this one？
脱线，我们成立一个非正式的行动小组如何？
Wait。What？
等等，什么？
You obviously have experience in the field.
你显然对这个领域很有经验
Yeah，I live right next to one.
是啊，我旁边就有一个
I don't know.
我也不知道了
I ain't exactly been much help to anybody recently.
最近我好像什么人也帮不上忙
You're helping me。Please，Mater.
你帮了我的忙，请吧，脱线
Well… Okay.
嗯，好吧
But you know I'm just a tow truck，right？
不过你知道我只是辆拖车吧？
Right。And I'm just in the import export business.
知道，我也只是做进出口贸易的嘛
- Siddeley？- Yes，Finn？
- 西德？- 什么，芬恩？
Paris。Tout de suite.
马上去巴黎
Yeah，two of them sweets for me，too，Sid.
是啊，他们两个对我也太好了，西德
I always wanted to be a spy.
我一直想当侦探
Really？Me，too.
真的吗？我也是
- Afterburners，sir？- Is there any other way？
- 要打开加力助燃吗，长官？- 还有其他办法吗？
Ha ha ha！
哈哈哈！
Once we're inside，stay close.
我们进去之后，要跟紧
Don't bother checking VIN numbers。They're all dodgy here.
不用费神查识别号码，这里的都是假的
Got it.
明白
Don't talk to anyone，don't look at anyone，
别和任何人说话，别看任何人
and absolutely，positively no idling。Are we clear？
而且绝对，千万不要闲逛，明白了吗？
Yes。No idling。Yes，sir.
好的，不要闲逛，没问题，长官
- Mater？- Yeah，Finn？
- 脱线？- 什么，芬恩？
- We're not here to go shopping。- Shoppin'？What do you mean？
- 我们不是来逛街的 - 逛街？什么意思？
Why would I…
我为什么…
Dad gum.
老天爷
- Part for sales，monsieur。- Monsieur，part for sale.
- 零件特卖，先生 - 先生，零件便宜卖
They got everything here。No！
这儿真是什么都有，看呀！
Look at them hoods！I could use a hood.
发动机罩！我缺一个发动机罩
Sorry，fellers。I gotta go！
抱歉了伙计，我得走了
Wow。Whoa。He-he！
哇噢，哇，嘻嘻！
Do what？
那是什么？
Excuse me。What are you selling？
打扰了，你卖的是什么？
Headlights，monsieur，headlights？
头灯，先生，头灯要吗？
- What in the？- Two for one.
- 里面是…？- 买一送一
- I give you good price！- I'm good！
- 给你优惠价格！- 不用了！
- There you are。- There is some great bargains here.
- 找到你了 - 这里有好些便宜货
- Mater，get back！- Imbile！
- 脱线，退后！- 不可能
Hey，wait for me！
嘿，等等我！
Ahhhhhh！
啊啊啊！
Ag-g-g-h！
啊！
- Have you lost your mind？- But I thought…
- 你疯了吗？- 我以为…
This chap needs a tow。Hook him up.
这家伙需要拖车，把他拖走
Sure thing.
包在我身上
You rusty piece of junk！Get your dirty hook off me！
你这个生锈的垃圾！把你的破钩子拿远点！
Electroshock！Are you kidding me？
电击！开什么玩笑？
This is her first field assignment。She didn't know you were my informant.
她第一次外出执勤，不知道你是我的线人
- Informant？- A rookie，huh？
- 线人？- 新手，哼？
I never liked new car smell.
我一向不喜欢新车的味道
Tomber was doing 20 to life in a Moroccan impound
如果没记错的话我第一次把托博尔救出来的时候
the first time I saved him，if I recall correctly.
他正在摩洛哥的拘留所里关着呢
Speaking of recalls，you're getting up there in mileage，aren't you？
说到回忆，你到那儿也没有白去吧？
All right，we get it。You both know each other，you're both old.
我明白了，你们两个认识，而且都是老爷车
So，here you go，informant。Inform us.
那就交给你了，线人，给我们线索吧
Beuck！That is the worst motor ever made.
哼！这真是最烂的发动机
Wait。That oil filter。Those wheel bearings.
等等，那个滤油器，还有那些轴承
Do those parts look familiar，Tomber？
托博尔，那些零件眼熟吗？
They should。I sold them.
应该眼熟，是我卖的
- To whom？- No idea.
- 卖给谁？- 不知道
He's my best customer，but he always does his business over the phone.
他是我最好的顾客，但他只通过电话下单
I was always wondering why he needs so many parts.
我一直奇怪他怎么需要那么多零件
Now I know.
现在明白了
A lemon needs parts。Ain't nothin' truer than that.
柠檬车就需要零件，这是千真万确的
- Lemon？- Yeah。Cars that don't ever work right.
- 柠檬车？- 对，那些天生就老出故障的车
Lemons is a tow truck's bread and butter.
柠檬车就是拖车的衣食父母
Like 'em Gremlins and Pacers we run into at the party
就像那些格里莫林和步行者，我们在晚会上碰见的
and the race and the airport.
还有赛场上和机场上
Pull up the pictures from the oil platform.
霍莉，拉出钻井平台上的照片
I want to know what other type of cars were out there.
我要知道还有其它什么型号的车在那里
Right。Let's see。There were Hugos and Trunkovs.
好，我们看看，还有雨果和特朗考夫
Are these cars considered lemons？
这些车也是柠檬车吗？
Is the Popemobile Catholic？
教皇专车是天主教徒吗？
Everyone involved in this plot is one of history's biggest loser cars.
每一辆被卷入阴谋的车都是史上最失败车型
And they're all taking their orders from the car behind this engine.
而且他们听从这台引擎背后那辆车的命令
- Ah。This explains it。- What，Tomber？
- 啊，这就解释得通了 - 怎么，托博尔？
Gremlin，Pacer，Hugo and Trunkov
格里莫林，步行者，雨果和特朗考夫
never get together，
他们从没一起出现过
but they are having a secret meeting in two days.
但他们这两天内有一个秘密集会
- Where's this meeting taking place？- Porto Corsa，Italy.
- 集会地点在哪儿？- 意大利波图科萨
That's where the next race is！
那是下场比赛的地点！
There's a good chance our mystery engine will be there，too.
也是个好机会在那儿见到我们的神秘引擎
Your chances are more than good.
简直是天赐良机
I just sent him a new clutch assembly yesterday.
我昨天刚给他送了一台离合器总成
To Porto Corsa.
发到波图科萨
Contact Stevenson and have him meet us at Gare de Lyon.
联络史蒂文森，让他在里昂车站与我们会合
Good work.
干得好
That three wheeled feller had to be right about a big meetin'.
那个三轮车说的集会的事肯定是真的
You never see this many lemons in one town.
还从来没在一个城市里见到这么多柠檬车呢
'Less there's a swap meet.
除非这儿有个跳蚤市场
How'd you get all them pictures？
你怎么拍到他们的照片的？
I reprogrammed Porto Corsa's red light cameras
我重写了波图科萨的交通摄像系统
to do recognition scans.
通过这个系统进行识别扫描
Wow。Not only is you the purtiest car I ever met，
哇，你不仅是我见过的车里最美的
but you're the smartest，too.
也是最聪明的
Thank you… I think.
谢谢你…我想
That's a familiar sight。A Hugo being towed.
多熟悉的场景啊，一辆雨果被拖走
But he looks absolutely perfect！
但他看起来完整无缺啊！
Of course！They must be the heads of the lemon families.
当然了！他们一定是柠檬车家族的头目
Makes sense。If I was rich and broke down every day，
有道理，我要是有钱，还每天出故障
I'd hire me to tow me around all the time，too！
我也会雇我自己拖着我自己走！
We've got to infiltrate that meeting to find out who's behind all this.
我们得潜入那个集会，看看是谁在操控
- Hang on a minute。Hold still。- Ow！
- 稍等，别动 - 噢！
Ah-ha。Good job，Miss Shiftwell.
啊哈！干得漂亮，灵智速小姐
Thank you，Finn.
谢谢，芬恩
Boy，I sure wish my friends could see me now.
天哪，真希望我朋友看看我现在的样子
LUIGl：Guido，your eyes do not deceive you.
圭多，你的眼睛没有欺骗你
We are in Italy。We are home.
我们在意大利，我们回家了
Hey，Luigi。Which way to the hotel，man？
嗨，路易吉，去旅馆怎么走？
What？No friend of mine will stay in a hotel in a my village.
什么？在我老家，绝不会让朋友去住旅馆
You will stay with my… Uncle Topolino-o-o-o！
你们住在我…叔叔托波利诺！
Luigi！Guido！
路易吉！圭多！
How do they do it？
他们是怎么做的？
These are the same ingredients as back home，
跟我们在家用的原料是一样的
but it tastes so good.
但味道怎么这么好
- It's organic，man。- Treehugger.
- 这是有机的，兄弟 - 你这个「拥抱树木」的嬉皮
Hey，race car.
嗨，赛车
You look so down，so low.
你看起来这么垂头丧气的
Is like you have flat tires.
好像轮胎没气了一样
She said you look like you are starving，
她说你看起来好像饿坏了
that she's gonna make you a big meal and fatten you up.
她要给你做顿大餐，把你喂的饱饱的
Oh，no.
哦，不是的
Mama Topolino，please，you don't need to make a fuss.
托波利诺妈妈，不用这么麻烦
Capisco。I understand.
我明白了
Is a problem，yes，between you and a friend？
朋友之间闹别扭了吧？
How did you know that？
您怎么知道的？
A wise car hears one word and understands two.
聪明的车一向善于察言观色
That，and Luigi told me.
那是路易吉告诉我的
While Mama cooks，come and take a stroll with me.
趁着妈妈做饭，跟我去散散步吧
I brought my friend Mater along on the trip
这次比赛我带我的朋友脱线一起来的
and I told him he needed to act different，
我告诉他得注意言行举止
that we weren't in Radiator Springs.
毕竟我们不是在油车水镇
This Mater is a close friend？
这位脱线是你很好的朋友吗？
He's my best friend.
他是我最好的朋友
Then why would you ask him to be someone else？
那为什么要让他变成另一个样子呢？
What did I do？
我做了什么？
I said some things during our fight.
我在我们争执的时候说了些话
You know，back when Guido and Luigi used to work for me，
以前圭多和路易吉帮我干活的时候
they would fight over everything.
他们为各种各样的事情争吵
They fight over what Ferrari was the best Ferrari，
哪种法拉利是最好的法拉利
which one of them looked more like a Ferrari.
他们哪一个更像法拉利
There were even some non Ferrari fights.
甚至还有跟法拉利无关的争吵
So I tell them，「Va bene，it's OK to fight.
我就告诉他们「没问题，吵就吵吧」
「Everybody fights now and then，especially best friends.
「每个人都吵架，特别是和最好的朋友」
「But you got to make up fast.
「但你们得赶快和好」
「No fight more important than friendship。」
「友谊比什么争执都重要」
- What does that mean？- Whoever find a friend，find a treasure.
- 那是什么意思？- 拥有朋友，就拥有财富
Now，mangia。Eat！
现在，小伙子，吃吧！
Finn，one hour to Porto Corsa.
芬恩，还有一小时到波图科萨
Thank you，Stevenson.
谢谢，史蒂文森
- That should just about do it。- Perfect.
- 应该差不多了 - 一级棒
So，Mater，it's voice activated.
行了，脱线，这是声控的
But everything's voice activated these days.
不过如今什么都是声控的啦
What？I thought you was supposed to be makin' me a disguise.
什么？我以为你们要给我做伪装呢
Voice recognized。Disguise program initiated.
声音已识别，伪装程序启动
Cool！
酷！
Computer，make me a German truck.
电脑，我要变德国卡车
- Request acknowledged。- Check it out！I'm wearing Materhosen.
- 请求已确认 - 看啊！我穿上背带裤了
Make me a monster truck！
我要变巨无霸卡车！
- Request acknowledged。- What the？
- 请求已确认 - 这是什么？
I vant to siphon your gas！
我要吸干你们的汽油！
- Now make me a taco truck！- Request acknowledged.
- 现在把我变成玉米卷售卖车！- 请求已确认
- A funny car！- Request acknowledged.
- 特种赛车！- 请求已确认
The idea is to keep a low profile，Mater.
伪装是为了不引起引人注意，脱线
So I just go in，pretend to be this truck.
那我就混进去，伪装成这辆卡车
- And leave the rest to us。- Now，hold still.
- 剩下的就交给我们了 - 现在别动
I have to do the final fitting on your disguise.
你的伪装还要做点最后的调整
That's no good。Hm.
这个不行
Hey。What are you doin'？
嘿，你要干嘛？
The disguise won't calibrate effectively without a smooth surface to graft onto.
表面不光滑的话，伪装会衔接不好
For a second there，I thought you was tryin' to fix my dents.
等一会儿，我猜你是要修补我的凹痕吧
- Yes，I was。- Then，no，thank you.
- 是的 - 不了，谢谢
I don't get them dents buffed，pulled，filled or painted by nobody.
我不想给我的凹痕抛光，填平，上漆什么的
- They way too valuable。- Your dents are valuable？Really？
- 它们很珍贵 - 凹痕很珍贵？真的吗？
I come by each one of 'em with my best friend，Lightning McQueen.
每道凹痕都是跟我最好的朋友麦坤一起玩弄上的
I don't fix these。I wanna remember these dents forever.
我不要修补，我要永远记住它们
So，you were being serious in Paris？
那巴黎的事是真的了？
McQueen isn't just part of your cover.
麦坤不只是你用来掩饰身份的？
Friendships can be dangerous in our line of work，Mater.
做我们这样的工作交朋友是很危险的，脱线
But my line of work is towin' and salvage.
但我的工作就是拖吊和援救啊
Right。And Miss Shiftwell's is designing iPhone apps.
是啊，灵智速小姐还是设计iPhone程序的呢
- No，I meant for real。- It's OK。I'll work around the dent.
- 不，我是说真的 - 没事没事，我在凹痕附近操作就行了
- Oh… - In the meantime…
- 哦 - 另外…
…you look a little light on weapons.
你好像还缺几把武器呢
You are looking live at beautiful
波图科萨，坐落于意大利的里维埃拉
Porto Corsa，Italy，on the Italian Riviera.
多么美丽而充满生气啊
What a magnificent setting for the second race of the World Grand Prix！
对于世界赛车大奖赛第二站来说环境非常理想
Well Brent，they call this place the 「Gem of the Riviera，」
是啊布伦特，此地被称为「里维埃拉的明珠」
and it's easy to see why.
原因不言而喻
With its secluded beaches and opulent casinos，
海滨幽静，赌场遍布
Porto Corsa truly is a playground for the wealthy.
波图科萨真是富人们的天堂
And everyone who's anyone is here today，
而今天，各路人士欢聚于此
from the ultra- rich and super- famous
从超级富豪到超级明星
to world leaders and important dignitaries.
和世界级的达官贵人
You aren't kidding，David.
你所言不虚，大卫
You can't do a three point turn without bumping into some celebrity.
只要做个三点转向，就会撞上个把名人
Welcome，everyone，to the second race of the World Grand Prix，
欢迎各位来到世界赛车大奖赛的第二站
where the big news continues to be allinol.
聚合油的新闻依然占据头条
Sir Miles Axlerod spoke to the press earlier today
麦尔斯·艾克斯勒洛德爵士于今天早些时候
to answer questions about its safety.
就安全性问题回答了媒体提问
An independent panel of scientists has determined
一支独立的科学调查团已经做出结论
that allinol is completely safe，okay？
认为聚合油是绝对安全的，行了吗？
Safe。There it is.
是安全的，就这样
So the race will go on，folks.
因此比赛会继续，观众们
But the question everyone is asking：
但每个人都关心的问题是：
Will the real Lightning McQueen show up today？
闪电麦坤会展现出他的冠军本色吗？
He'd better。Talk about a home track advantage.
最好是这样，说到主场优势
Francesco Bernoulli grew up racing on this course.
弗朗西斯科·伯努利就是在这种赛道上长大的
Signore e signori，in the pole position，Numero Uno，Francesco！
女士们先生们，成绩领先的1号，弗朗西斯科！
Bellissima！Thank you for your support！
美女们！谢谢你们的支持！
And your big mistake，McQueen！
也谢谢你的重大失误，麦坤！
In secondo position，
屈居第二位的
numero 95，Lightning-a McQueen-a！
95号，闪电麦坤！
McQueen-a，is a everything OK？
麦坤，你没事吧？
If you're worried about your fuel，man，don't。It's perfectly safe.
如果你担心燃料，那没必要，它绝对安全
No，guys，I just really wish Mater were here.
不是，我只是希望脱线也在这儿
Francesco understands，McQueen.
弗朗西斯科理解你，麦坤
Oh，great，here it comes.
哦，又来了
What do you got，Francesco？
你想说什么，弗朗西斯科？
For famous race cars like Francesco and，
对于著名的赛车来说，比如弗朗西斯科
well，you，
当然还有你
to be far away from home is not easy.
远离家乡是很难过的
I think you forgot the insulting part of that insult.
你好像忘了损我了
Is a no insult.
我不是损你
When a Francesco is away from home，he misses his mama，
弗朗西斯科出门在外的时候，会想念他的妈妈
just like a you miss your tow truck amico.
就像你想念你的拖车朋友一样
Gee，I maybe misjudged you，because that's exactly…
天，我以前是不是误会了你，这实在是…
Of course，I am at home，and my mama is right here.
当然了，现在我就在家门口，而且我妈妈就在那儿
Mama！
妈妈！
Don't worry，Mama，McQueen is very sad.
别担心，妈妈，麦坤很不开心
I will beat his cry baby bottom today！
今天我会打这个爱哭宝宝的屁屁的！
And there's the insult we were missing.
这才到损我的部分
Darrell，the racers are settling in as they head
达雷尔，赛车们已经就位了
to the Italian countryside.
正向着意大利乡村进发
Whoo，boy！
喔，小伙子们！
This is gonna be a great race.
这将是一场伟大的比赛
Gremlins。Man，those are some ugly cars.
格里莫林，伙计们，这些车可真丑
Look like someone stole their trunks.
就像有谁想偷他们的后备箱似的
My grand a father has a broken down.
我的祖父抛锚了
If a one of a you would help，I would be so thankful.
要是有谁能帮一把，我会感激不尽的
Sounds like you need some roadside assistance.
听起来你需要道路援助
- She was talking to me。- Really？Prove it.
- 她跟我说话呢 - 是吗？谁能证明？
Don't a fight over me.
别因为我吵架
Signore Tow Truck，per favore.
拖车先生，劳驾了
Get ready，Mater。You're on any moment now.
准备好，脱线，随时行动
I don't know about this。What if I screw things up？
我不会啊，要是搞砸了怎么办？
Impossible.
不可能
Just apply the same level of dedication
正常发挥就好
you've been using to play the idiot tow truck，and you'll be fine.
演好傻瓜拖车的角色就可以了
It's just that them guys look purty tough and…
可是那些家伙看起来很难对付…
Wait，did you say 「idiot」？
等等，你说「傻瓜」？
- Is that how you see me？- That's how everyone sees you.
- 你是这么看我的？- 每个人都这么看你的
Isn't that the idea？
那不是你的策略吗？
I tell you，that's the genius of it.
我跟你说，这就是你的天才之处
No one realizes they're being fooled
谁都意识不到自己被你耍了
because they're too busy laughing at the fool.
因为他们光顾着嘲笑那个傻瓜了
Brilliant！
真高明！
- Why aren't you in disguise？- I er…
- 你怎么还没伪装好？- 我…
- Come on！There's no time！Go！- OK。OK.
- 快点！没时间了！赶紧！- 好吧，好吧
- Computer，disguise！- Request acknowledged.
- 电脑，伪装！- 请求已确认
It's the boss。He's coming.
老板来了
Ivan.
伊万
Oh，er…
哦，呃…
Ivan，why do you insult me so by making me wait here？
伊万，你怎么这么无礼，把我晾在这里？
He's in.
他上场了
The racers are now making their way around the hairpin
赛车们正在绕着U型弯道转弯
and headed downhill toward the casino bridge.
然后向山下的赌场桥开去
No more bets，please.
请停止下注
Come on，fuzzy dice！
来吧，绒毛骰子！
- Number four。Easy four。- Yeah！
- 四点 - 耶！
Air freshener。Antenna balls.
空气清新剂，天线球
Spark a plugs.
火花塞
This place looks like it's made outta gold！
这地方看起来像是金子砌的！
That's because it is。Now，be careful what you say.
因为它就是，现在说话要注意
Why is that？
为啥？
What do you mean，「Don't talk to ya」？
什么叫「不要跟你说话」？
You want me to stop talkin' to ya right now？
你要我现在就不要跟你说话吗？
You are acting strange today，Ivan.
你今天怪怪的，伊万
I have no idea what you're talking about，
不知道你说什么
「Alexander Hugo，aka Chop Shop Alex。」
「亚历克桑德·雨果，也叫拆车铺亚历克斯」
You got a lot of aka's，Alex.
你的名字还真多，亚历克斯
But that makes sense，
不过也有道理
seein's how you's wanted in France，Germany…
你看，你在这么多国家都被通缉，法国，德国…
Mater，stop it！
脱线，住嘴！
OK，OK，keep your voice down！
行了行了，小点声！
You gonna make me arrested！
你要招来警察了！
Don't mess with Ivan today。He's in a bad mood.
今天别惹伊万，他心情不好
He's so good！
他真出色！
Victor！
维克多！
Hey，Victor！
嗨，维克多！
- There you are！- Come in！
- 你来了！- 请进！
Victor Hugo，I'm J Curby Gremlin。From Detroit.
维克多·雨果，我是J·科比·格里莫林，从底特律来
It's good to see you.
很高兴见到你
Is the big boss here yet？
大老板来了吗？
- No，not yet。- He's supposed to be here any minute.
- 还没有 - 他应该随时会来
Here we go.
要出场了
Guten Tag.
日安
It's just the professor.
只是教授而已
Zedapp！When is he coming？
泽达普，他什么时候来？
He's already here.
他已经到了
Welcome，everyone.
各位好
I wish I could be with you on this very special day，
我真希望能诸位共同庆祝这个特殊的日子
but my clutch assembly broke.
但我的离合器总成坏了
- You know how it is。- Forget about it.
- 你们了解是怎么回事 - 别提了
We know how you feel.
我们了解你的感受
- Descramble that voice。- I'm trying.
- 解码那个声音 - 我正在尝试
Oh，it's too sophisticated.
噢，太复杂了
We are here to celebrate.
我们是来此庆祝的
Today，all your hard work pays off.
今天，所有的努力将得到回报
The world turned their backs on cars like us.
我们这样的车被整个世界所抛弃
They stopped manufacturing us，stopped making our parts.
他们停止生产我们，停止制造我们的配件
The only thing they haven't stopped doing is laughing at us.
唯一没有停止的就是嘲笑我们
They've called us terrible names：Jalopy，rust bucket，heap，
给我们起丑陋的名字：老爷车，锈铁桶，废铁堆
clunker，junker，beater，wreck，rattletrap，
旧机器，破汽车，旧汽车，破烂儿，破铜烂铁
lemon.
柠檬车
But their insults just give us strength.
但他们的侮辱赐予我们力量
Because today，my friends，that all ends！
因为到了今天，我的朋友们，一切都将结束！
There's smoke on the casino bridge！
赌场桥上冒烟了！
Oh，no！
哦不！
It's Carla Veloso，the Brazilian race car！
是卡拉·维罗索，巴西赛车！
- What just happened？- I'm working on it.
- 出什么事了？- 我正在查
They laughed at us，but now it's our turn to laugh back.
他们嘲笑我们，但现在轮到我们嘲笑他们了
Another crash！It's number 9，Nigel Gearsley.
又一起故障！是9号，奈杰尔·吉斯利
Embrace your inner lemon.
拥抱你们自己的柠檬吧
Let it drive you.
让它来驱动你
I'm detecting an extremely strong electromagnetic pulse.
我检测到一股极强的电磁脉冲
- Finn，it's the camera。- Where？
- 芬恩，是那台摄像机 - 在哪儿？
On the tower！
塔上！
This was meant to be alternative fuel's greatest moment.
这将成为新燃料最伟大的时刻
But after today，everyone will race back to gasoline.
但今天过后，每个人都会用回汽油
And we，the owners of the world's largest untapped oil reserve
而我们，世界最大的未开发原油储备的拥有者
will become the most powerful cars in the world！
将成为世界上最有权势的汽车！
Get out of the way！
闪开！
They will come to us，and they will have no choice，because they will need us.
他们会回来找我们，别无选择，因为他们需要我们
Huh？Whoa！
啊？！
We figured you might stop by！
我们算准了你会来！
And they will finally respect us！
他们最终会尊敬我们！
So hold your hoods high！
高举你们的引擎盖吧！
After today，you will never again be ashamed of who you are！
今天过后，你们再也不用为自己的身份而羞愧了！
No！
不！
Long live lemons！
柠檬车万岁！
Number 7 is loose！Shu Todoroki！
7号车爆胎了，轰木秀！
Finn？
芬恩？
Bumper to bumper as they approach the finish line！
他们以微弱差距冲过终点线！
McQueen's the winner！Francesco's second！
麦坤获胜！弗朗西斯科第二名！
They have no idea what happened behind them.
他们完全不知道身后发生了什么事
This is impossible！
这不可能！
That's what I'm talking about！Ka-chow！
这才是我嘛！咔嚓！
What happened？
出什么事了？
- Where are all the other cars？- What is going on？
- 其他车呢？- 怎么了？
Oh，no！
哦，不！
Sir Axlerod，is the final race in London still going to take place？
艾克斯勒洛德爵士，伦敦最后一站还会如期举行吗？
I suppose that…
我认为…
The show must go on，as they say.
比赛必须进行下去，就像他们说的那样
I can't believe this is really happening！
真不敢相信居然成功了！
Quiet！
安静！
Will you require all the racers to still run on allinol？
你会要求所有赛车依然使用聚合油燃料吗？
I cannot，in good conscience，continue to risk the lives of any more race cars.
凭良心说，我不能继续拿任何赛车来冒险了
The final race will not be run on allinol.
终点赛不需要使用聚合油
There you have it，
观众们都看到了
a clearly devastated Sir Miles Axlerod
麦尔斯·艾克斯勒洛德爵士显然深受打击
announcing that he will not require the cars to use allinol for the final race.
宣布他不再要求选手在终点赛上使用聚合油
A toast！
干杯！
To the death of allinol and alternative fuel forever！
祝贺聚合油和新能源永远灭亡！
Mater，abort the mission.
脱线，任务中止
They've got Finn。Get out of there。Get out of there right now.
他们抓走了芬恩，离开这里，马上离开
How is your grandfather？
你祖父怎么样了？
Long live lemons！
柠檬万岁！
Isn't this a great party，Ivan，huh？
这派对真棒，嗯？
Oh，yeah，it's unbelievable.
是啊，难以置信
You are not leaving，are you？
你不会要走吧？
Uh… of course I ain't leaving.
呃…我当然不走
- McQUEEN ON TV：I'm just in shock… - McQueen？
- 我感到十分震惊 - 麦坤？
Crashes are a part of racing，I know，
我知道出故障是比赛中的常事
but something like that should never happen.
但像这样的事故从没发生过
You can choose your fuel for the final race。What it'll be？
在决赛中你会选择什么燃料？
Allinol.
聚合油
After today？
即使出了今天这样的事？
My friend Fillmore says it's safe。That's good enough for me.
我朋友菲尔莫说它是安全的，对我来说就足够了
I didn't stand by a friend of mine recently.
最近我不够信任我的一位朋友
I'm not gonna make the same mistake twice.
我不会再次犯同样的错误
So a surprising revelation from Lightning McQueen.
闪电麦坤发表了惊人的宣言
He will use allinol in the final race，despite what occurred today.
他将不顾今天的事故，继续在决赛中使用聚合油
- …till Lightning McQueen is dead。- Of course.
- …直到闪电麦坤死掉 - 没问题
Allinol must be finished for good.
聚合油必须永久性终结
McQueen cannot win the last race.
麦坤不能赢决赛
Lightning McQueen must be killed！
闪电麦坤必须被清除！
No！
不要！
It's the American spy！
那个美国间谍！
Dad gum！
这回够呛了！
Gatling gun。Request acknowledged.
格特林机枪，请求已确认
Down！Everybody，down！
趴下，所有人趴下！
Shoot！I didn't mean… Request acknowledged.
哇塞！我说的不是「枪」… 请求已确认
Wait！Wait！I didn't mean that kind of shoot！
等等！等等！我说的不是「发射」！
Correction acknowledged。Deploying chute.
更正已确认，发送降落伞
Whoa！
哇！
McQueen！
麦坤！
Whoa！What's this？
哇！那是什么？
Whoa！
哇！
McQueen！McQueen！
麦坤！麦坤！
Waagh！
啊！
Let me through！Let me through！
让我过去！让我过去！
Let me in！I got to get through to warn McQueen！
让我进去！我要去警告麦坤！
You cannot a come through here！Back up.
你不能进去！后退
We have a lunatic at gate 9.
9号门这儿有个疯子
I was disguised as a tow truck to infiltrate this lemonhead meeting
我伪装成一辆拖车混进柠檬车头目的聚会
and my weapons system's done misinterperated what I'm saying！
我的武器系统理解错了我的话
- Lunatic at gate 9。- McQueen！McQueen！
- 9号门有疯子 - 麦坤！麦坤！
- You are the champion！- This way，signore.
- 你是冠军！- 走这边，先生
- McQueen！- Mater？
- 麦坤！- 脱线！
- McQueen。- Give us a pose！
- 麦坤 - 摆个姿势！
- McQueen！- Stop moving。Stop！
- 麦坤！- 别动，停下！
Where you going？
你去哪儿？
Stop！
停下！
- McQueen！- That really sounded like…
- 麦坤！- 听起来真像…
Mater！
脱线！
- Mater？- Signore？
- 脱线？- 先生？
McQueen！They're gonna kill you！
麦坤！他们要杀了你！
Mater！
脱线！
Excuse me.
抱歉
No，where are you going？
别，你要去哪儿？
Scusi。Mater！
脱线！
- McQueen！- Scusi.
- 麦坤！- 对不起
Mater！Mater！
脱线！脱线！
Mater，I'm so glad to see you.
脱线，看见你真高兴
Lightning McQueen！I am a huge fan.
闪电麦坤！我是你的忠实粉丝
I'm sorry，I thought I heard…
抱歉，我还以为我看见了…
That was me.
是我对你说话
I said，「You killed out there today。You're the best。」
我说「你今天杀了其他车的风头，你是最棒的」
- What？I mean，thanks。- Right this way，signore.
- 什么？我是说谢谢 - 走这边，先生
I really thought I heard my friend.
我真的以为听见了我朋友的声音
In England，you'll be finished！At the finish line.
在英国，你会走到终点的！就在终点线
- Wait，what？- The press is waiting.
- 等等，什么？- 媒体在等着呢
Come a with me，please.
请跟我来
Let me go！
放开我！
You actually care about that race car.
你真是很关心那辆赛车
A pity you didn't warn him in time.
可惜你没能及时通知他
「Idiot」？Is that how you see me？
「傻瓜」？你是这么看我的？
That's how everyone sees you。I tell you，that's the genius of it.
我跟你说，这就是你的天才之处
No one realizes they're being fooled
谁都意识不到自己被你耍了
because they're too busy laughing at the fool.
因为他们光顾着嘲笑那个傻瓜了
At the fool…
嘲笑那个傻瓜…
Excuse me！
借过！
Domo arigato！
我是多摩君！
Yeah！
耶！
You done good。You got all the leaves.
你干得不错，把叶子都清干净了
- Check out that tow truck。- I wonder who that guy's with.
- 看那个拖车 - 不知道是跟谁一起来的
Will you guys excuse me just for one little second？
不好意思，我离开一小会儿
Now that's a scoop of ice cream！
这就对了嘛，一大勺冰激凌！
Aargh！
啊！
Somebody get me water！Oh，sweet relief.
谁能给我点水！哦，凉快多了
Mater！
脱线！
But I never leak oil。Never.
可我从来不漏油的，从来不
Get a hold of yourself。You're making a scene！
脱线，控制一下你自己，别出丑了
Wait a minute。I didn't screw you up，did I？
等等，我没给你添乱吧？
- I lost the race because of you！- Maybe if I talked to somebody…
- 我输了比赛，就因为你！- 也许我能跟什么人说说…
I don't need your help！
我不需要你帮忙！
I don't want your help.
我不想要你帮忙！
Your help…
你帮忙…
Bang the gong。Get it on！
咣咣咣，开始啦！
Listen，this isn't Radiator Springs.
听着，这里不是油车水镇
This is exactly why I don't bring you along to these things！
这就是为什么我不带你到这种场合来！
Holley！Finn！Where are we？
霍莉！芬恩！我们在哪儿？
We're in London，Mater，inside Big Bentley.
我们在伦敦，脱线，大本钟里面
Whoa！
哇！
Oh，this… This is all my fault.
哦，这是…这都是我的错
Don't be a fool，Mater.
别傻了，脱线
But I am，remember？You said so.
但我就是傻瓜，记得吗？你说的
When did I… Oh.
我什么时候…噢
Mater，I was complimenting you on what a good spy you are.
脱线，我那是在夸你是个出色的侦探
I'm not a spy！
我不是侦探！
I've been trying to tell you that the whole time.
我一直都想告诉你们这个
I really am just a tow truck.
我真的只是辆拖车
Finn，he's not joking.
芬恩，他没开玩笑
- I know。- You were right，Finn。I'm a fool.
- 我知道了 - 你说的对，芬恩，我是个傻瓜
And what's happened to McQueen is 'cause I'm such a big one.
麦坤出事都是因为我这个大傻瓜
This is all my fault.
都是我的错
- Good。You're up。- And just in time.
- 很好，你们醒了 - 正是时候
Professor Z wanted you to have a front row seat，
Z教授想让你们近距离欣赏闪电麦坤之死
- He's still alive？- Not for much longer.
- 他还活着？- 活不长了
Whoa！
哇！
Huh？
啊？
- We came as soon as you called。- I called to talk to Mater.
- 你一打电话我们就来了 - 我想找脱线
It never occurred to me he wouldn't be there.
他从来都没有不在家的时候
Sheriff is talking to Scotland Yard now.
治安官去找苏格兰场了
And Sarge is in touch with his friends in the British military.
警官在联系他在英国部队的朋友
You just need to focus on the race.
你只要专心比赛就好了
I know but，Sally
我知道，不过莎莉
with everything going on，I'm not sure…
看发生的这些事情，我不确定…
- Sir Axlerod。- I'm sorry to interrupt.
- 艾克斯勒洛德爵士 - 抱歉打扰了
- It's all right。- I just wanted to personally thank you.
- 没关系 - 我只想当面谢谢你
Because after Italy，I was finished，
意大利赛之后，我本来已经绝望了
and then you gave me one last shot.
但你给了我最后的希望
Listen…
听我说…
I probably shouldn't be saying this，but I hope you win today.
我也许不该这么说，但我希望你能赢
You show the world that they've been wrong about allinol.
展示给全世界看，聚合油没有问题
Mater would want you to race.
脱线会想让你比赛的
All right。For Mater.
好的，为了脱线
Here he comes.
他过来了
- What happened？- I don't know，Professor.
- 怎么回事？- 我不知道，教授
- What did you do？- I didn't do nothing.
- 你干什么了？- 我什么也没干
Ssh，I'm talking to the Professor。What's that，Professor？
嘘，我在和教授说话，你说什么，教授？
- You broke it！- Quiet！
- 你把它弄坏了！- 安静！
- I understand，sir。Yes。- What did he say？
- 我明白了，先生，好的 - 他说什么？
- We go to the back up plan。- Back up plan？
- 我们要执行后备计划了 - 后备计划？
We snuck a bomb in McQueen's pit.
我们在麦坤的维修站里放了炸弹
The next time he makes a stop，instead of saying 「ka chow」…
下次他停下来的时候，他不会说「咔嚓」了
he's going to go 「ka boom」！
他会说「咔砰」！
Don't feel bad，tow truck。You couldn't have saved him.
别伤心了，拖车，你不可能救他的
Oh，wait，you could have！
哦，不对，你本来可以！
Dad gum lemons！Request acknowledged.
该死的柠檬车！请求已确认
What？You didn't think we'd take your bullets？
什么？你以为我们不会拿走你的子弹？
That's right！You got nothing！
就是，你什么都没了！
Who's the lemon now，huh？
现在谁是柠檬车了，嗯？
Nice try，Mater.
你尽力了，脱线
- Dad gum… Dad gum… Dad gum。- Request… Request… Request…
- 枪…枪…枪… - 请求…请求…请求…
Mater！
脱线！
I got to get y'all out of there.
我要把你们弄出这里
There's no time。McQueen needs your help.
没时间了，你得去帮麦坤
But I can't。I'm just a tow truck.
我帮不了啊，我只是辆拖车
It's up to you。Go to the pits and get everyone out.
全看你的了，去维修站把大家救出去
- You can do that。- What about you guys？
- 你行的 - 那你们呢？
- We'll be OK。- Go and get some more dents，Mater.
- 我们会没事的 - 去弄几个新的凹痕吧，脱线
So，we'll be OK？Really？
我们会没事？真的吗？
He wouldn't have left if I'd told him the truth.
如果告诉他真相，他就不会走了
Argh！
啊！
Being killed by a clock.
死在钟的手里
Gives a whole new meaning to 「Your time has come。」
应了那句老话「你的时间到了」
Time？That's it！
时间？对了！
- What are you doing？- Trying to turn back time.
- 你在干什么？- 试试把时间拨回去
If I can just reverse the polarity.
只要能把电极对调就好了
Good job。Quick thinking，Holley.
干的漂亮，脑子转得很快啊，霍莉
What's everybody on the wrong side of the road for？
怎么大家都在反的一边开车啊？
Oh，no！
噢，不是吧！
Drive！Burn rubber！
发动！紧急加速
We've got to get to the course.
我们得去赛场
Calculate the fastest way to…
计算最近的路线…
Done.
好了
Oh。Miss Shiftwell.
哦，灵智速小姐
- They're standard issue now。- You kids get all the good hardware.
- 现在都是标配了 - 你们年轻人真是装备一新
Oh，no，that's Mater's.
哦不，这是脱线的
我就知道他逃脱得太容易了
Come back here！Stop！
回来！停下！
- Mater？- Everybody，get out now！
- 脱线？- 大家马上出去！
Y'all get out of the pits。What are you guys doing here？
你们得离开维修站，你们怎么在这儿？
- We're here because of you，Mater。- Is everything OK？
- 我们因为你来的啊，脱线 - 一切都好吗？
No，everything's not OK。There's a bomb in here.
不，一切都不好，这里有个炸弹
- Y'all got to get out。Now。- A bomb？
- 你们马上出去 - 炸弹？
- Mater。- Finn！You're OK.
- 脱线 - 芬恩！你没事
Listen to me。The bomb is on you！They knew you'd try to help McQueen.
听我说，炸弹在你身上！他们知道你会去帮麦坤
When we were knocked out，they planted it in your air filter.
我们昏迷的时候，他们换掉了你的空气过滤器
- Uh-oh。- Mater！There you are！
- 啊哦 - 脱线，你在这儿！
- Stop right there！- I've been so worried about you.
- 停在那儿！- 我一直很担心你
- Don't come any closer！- Are you OK？
- 别再靠近了！- 你还好吧？
No，I'm not OK！Stay away from me！
不，我不好，离我远点儿！
No，wait！Wait！
不，等等！等等！
A tow truck has just raced onto the track，driving backwards！
一辆拖车上了跑道，倒退着开！
Mater，wait！
脱线，等等！
Normally an emergency vehicle on the track means there's been an accident.
通常紧急设备出现在跑道上意味着有事故发生
- Lightning McQueen is chasing him！- Mater，wait！
- 闪电麦坤在追他！- 脱线，等等！
Stay back！If you get close to me，you're going to get hurt real bad！
后退！你要是离我太近了，会受重伤的！
I know I made you feel that way before，but none of that matters！
我知道之前我伤害了你，不过其它都不重要了！
We're best friends！
我们是最好的朋友！
And McQueen seems to be having
麦坤与拖车之间
a conversation with the tow truck.
好像在进行一场对话
I don't know who that truck is，Brent，but tell you what，
我不知道这拖车是谁，布伦特，不过跟你说
he's got to be the world's best backwards driver.
他一定是全世界最会倒开的车
McQueen，you don't get it！I'm the bomb！
麦坤，你没明白，我就是炸弹！
Yes，Mater！You are the bomb！That's what I'm trying to say here！
是的，脱线！你是炸弹，我也想这么说！
You've always been the bomb and you'll always be the bomb.
你一直都是炸弹，永远都是炸弹
- Stay away！- No！Never！
- 躲开！- 决不！
Almost there.
差不多了
I'm not letting you get away again！
我不会再让你跑掉的！
Got to keep away from McQueen！Request acknowledged.
让麦坤离远点！请求已确认
Oh，my gosh.
哦，天哪
What is happening？It's a bad dream！
怎么回事？我在做噩梦吧！
And Lightning McQueen just blasted away，
闪电麦坤飙起来了
hooked to the now rocket propelled tow truck.
挂在一辆火箭驱动的拖车后面
Gargh！
啊！
The Professor's on the run！
教授跑了！
- Someone's got to get McQueen。- Get McQueen！
- 得有人去抓麦坤 - 去抓麦坤！
- Holley，I'll get Zedapp。Help Mater。- Got it！
- 霍莉，我去抓泽达普，你去帮脱线 - 收到！
What is happening？
到底是怎么回事？
Hurry，Professor.
快，教授
You really think I'm going to let you float away，Professor？
我以为我会让你溜之大吉吗，教授？
- McQueen，let go！- Never！
- 麦坤，放开！- 决不！
- They're coming your way。- Let's go！
- 他们朝你这边来了 - 我们上！
Give it up，McMissile.
放手吧，麦导弹
- Mater，stop！- No way！You could get hurt.
- 脱线，停下！- 不可能！你会受伤的
Oh，no.
哦不
Mater，we've got to get that bomb off you.
脱线，我们得把炸弹拆掉
Bomb？
炸弹？
Yeah，they strapped it to me to kill you as a back up plan.
是啊，他们在我身上绑了炸弹要杀你，这是后备计划
Back up plan？Mater，who put a bomb on you？
后备计划？脱线，谁在你身上放的炸弹？
You！Why didn't my death ray kill you？
你！为什么我的死亡射线没杀了你？
Death ray？
死亡射线？
Turn off the bomb，Zedapp！
关掉炸弹，泽达普！
Are you all so dense？
你们都这么笨啊？这是声控的
It's voice activated.
现在什么都是声控的
Deactivate！Deactivate！
解除！解除！
Voice denied.
无效声音
- Huh！- Oops.
- 啊！- 哎哟
Did I forget to mention that it can only be disarmed
我是不是忘了说
by the one who activated it？
只有启动者的声音才能解除它？
- Say it。- Deactivate.
- 说 - 解除
Voice denied.
无效声音
I'm not the one who activated it。Would anyone else like to try？
我不是启动者，还有其他人想试试吗？
- You read my mind。- He was getting on my nerves.
- 真是心有灵犀 - 他把我惹火了
- What do we do？- It's very simple。You blow up.
- 我们怎么办？- 很简单，你被炸飞
I'm going out on a limb here.
我愿意冒一回险
These are the guys that want me dead，correct？
这些就是想要我们命的家伙，对吧？
- It's nothing personal。- Fellers，listen.
- 这与个人恩怨无关 - 伙计们，听我说
I know what you're going through.
我知道你们经历过什么
Everybody's been laughing at me too.
人们也一直嘲笑我来着
But becoming powerful and rich beyond your wildest dreams
但就算有权有势的野心满足了
ain't gonna make you feel better.
也不能让你们更好受啊
Yeah，but it's worth a shot.
是啊，不过值得一试
Pit stop.
进维修站吧
Not today，boys.
不是今天，伙计们
Retreat！
撤退！
Thanks for the help，Corporal.
多谢帮忙，下士
Anything for one of Pop's mates.
愿为老兄你的朋友效劳
What's he saying？What's wrong？
他说什么？有什么问题？
None of his wrenches fit the bolts.
他的扳手没有一个适合这些螺栓的
I get it。I get it！
我知道了，我知道了！
- I know what needs to be done。- Then do it！
- 我怎么该怎么办了 - 那就赶紧呀！
What？No。I can't do it.
什么？不行，我办不到
Nobody takes me seriously.
没人拿我当真
I know that now.This ain't Radiator Springs.
我现在知道了，这里不是油车水镇
Yes，it is.
不，是一样的
Look，you're yourself in Radiator Springs.
在油车水镇，你就是你
Be yourself here.
在这里，你还是你
And if people aren't taking you seriously，
如果别人不拿你当真
then they need to change，not you.
那是他们需要改变，不是你
I know that because I was wrong before.
我之所以知道，是因为我以前错了
Now，you can do this。You're the bomb.
现在你可以办到的，你就是炸弹
Thanks，buddy.
谢谢你，哥们儿
No，you're the actual bomb。Now，let's go！
不，你现在是真的炸弹，我们马上走！
Oh，right。Hang on！
哦对，稳住了！
Where's he going？
他要去哪儿？
- Computer！- Yes，Agent Mater？
- 电脑！- 脱线探员请指示？
I need that thing you done before to get me away from McQueen！
我需要之前让我甩掉麦坤的那个东西
Request acknowledged.
请求已确认
- Mater？- Now I need you to do the chute！
- 脱线？- 现在我需要你发射了！
The second kind，not the first！
第二种，不是第一种！
Deploying chute
降落伞发射
Who's winning the race？
谁赢了比赛啊？
- Back off！Back away！- It's Lightning McQueen！
- 退后！退后！- 是闪电麦坤！
No，it's OK！Tell 'em，Mater。Explain.
不不，没事的，告诉他们，脱线，解释吧
Okay.
好的
Somebody's been sabotaging the racers and hurtin' the cars，and I know who.
有人一直在破坏比赛和赛车，我知道是谁
Oh，wait。Your Majesty.
噢，等一下，参见女王陛下
Bomb！It's a bomb！
炸弹！有炸弹！
- Everybody，down！- Back up！Move it！
- 所有人趴下！- 退后！转移！
Get off the stage！Move it！
离开主席台！快走！
Hold your fire！He can't disarm it！
住手！他能解除炸弹！
Mater，I don't know what you're doing，but stand down now.
脱线，我不知你要干什么，不过先退下去
This ain't nothing at all like Radiator Springs.
这里跟油车水镇一点也不一样
Mater，just cut to the chase.
脱线，直接说重点
Okay。It's him.
好的，就是他
What？Me？You've got to be crazy.
什么？我？你疯了吧
I figured it out when I realized y'all attached
我发现你用惠特沃斯螺栓固定这些炸弹的时候
this ticking time bomb with Whitworth bolts
就明白怎么回事了
the same bolts that hold together that old British engine from the photograph.
跟照片上的英国引擎用的一样的螺栓
- Holley！Show that picture。- OK.
- 霍莉！放照片 - 好的
I remembered what they say about old British engines：
我记得他们是这么说老式英国引擎的：
If there ain't no oil under 'em，there ain't no oil in 'em.
如果下面没有漏油，就说明里面没有油
What is he talking about？
他说什么呢？
It was you leaking oil at the party in Japan.
在日本的晚会上是你在漏油
You just blamed it on me.
却栽到我头上
Electric cars don't use oil，you twit.
电动车根本不用油，你这个傻瓜
Then you're fakin' it。You didn't convert to no electric.
那是你伪装的，你根本没改装成电动车
If we pop that hood，we'll see that engine from that picture.
如果我们打开引擎盖，就能看见那张照片里的引擎
This lorry's crazy！He's going to kill us all！
这辆卡车疯了！他要把我们都杀死！
Stay away！
别过来！
But Sir Axlerod created the race.
可比赛是艾克斯勒洛德发起的
Why would he want to hurt anyone？
他为什么要伤害选手？
To make allinol look bad
为了让聚合油看起来很危险
so everybody'd go back to using oil.
这样人们就会重新用汽油了
He said it himself with that disguised voice.
他自己用伪装过的声音说的
Disguised voice？What are you talking about？You're nuts，you are！
伪装的声音？你在说什么呢？你真是疯了！
This is going nowhere fast.
一时半会儿不会有结果的
We really should go，Grandmother.
我们真的该走了 奶奶
One moment，I'd like to see where this is going.
再等一下，我想看看会发生什么
Mater，he created allinol.
脱线，是他发明了聚合油
But what if he found that huge oil field
但如果他发现了巨大的油田呢？
just as the world was trying to find something else？
就在全世界都在寻找替代品的时候？
What if he came up with allinol
如果他制造出聚合油的目的
just to make alternative fuel look bad？
只是想让替代能源看起来很危险呢？
「What if」？You're basing this on a 「what if」？
「如果」？你没有证据，全都是假设吗？
- Okay，that's it。- Lads，clear out.
- 行了，就这样吧 - 伙计们，清场
Wait！Somebody save me！The lorry's crazy！
等等！得有人救我！这卡车疯了！
- Keep away，you idiot！- Mater！
- 别过来，你这个白痴！- 脱线！
- Mater！- Someone do something！
- 脱线！- 没人采取措施吗！
You're insane，you are！Deactivate！
你真是疯了！解除！
Bomb deactivated。Have a nice day，Sir Axlerod.
炸弹已解除，艾克斯勒洛德爵士祝您愉快
- The engine from the photo。- It's a perfect match.
- 这就是照片上的引擎 - 完全吻合
How did the tow truck figure it out？
一辆拖车怎么会知道的？
It's official。You're coming to all my races from now on.
说定了，以后你要参加我所有的比赛
Now you're talkin'！
这可是你说的！
Mater，let's go。You're on.
脱线，我们走，该你上场了
Your Majesty，may I present
女王陛下，请允许我
for the investiture of honorary knighthood of the British Realm…
将大英帝国的荣誉骑士勋章
Tow Mater of Radiator Springs.
授予来自油车水镇的拖车脱线
Go get 'em，buddy.
去吧，哥们儿
I hereby dub thee Sir Tow Mater.
我在此授予拖车脱线爵士称号
Sir？Shoot，you can just call me Mater，Your Majesty.
爵士？哇塞，您叫我脱线就行，女王陛下
I don't wanna hear none of this 「sir」 business.
我再也不想听到跟「爵士」沾边的东西了
By the way，have y'all met each other？
顺便为你们介绍一下
Queen，McQueen。McQueen，Queen.
女王，麦坤，麦坤，女王
McQueen，McMissile。McMissile，McQueen。Queen，McMissile.
麦坤，麦导弹，麦导弹，麦坤，女王，麦导弹
So there we was，my rocket jets going full blast，
当时呢，我的火箭助推器全速开动
McQueen hanging on for dear life
麦坤不顾死活地挂在我后面
when suddenly them two nasty lemons come out of nowheres，guns drawed.
然后那些卑鄙的柠檬车突然冒出来，还带着枪
We was goners.
我们眼看要完蛋了
But then，out of nowhere this beautiful spy car
但就在这时，漂亮的间谍车突然出现
swoops in from the sky to save us！
从天而降救了我们！
That's a very entertaining story，young man.
这故事真有意思，年轻人
Oh，Minny，please。Come on！
哦，明妮，得了吧！
None of this happened。Rocket jets，flying spy cars.
都是编的，什么火箭助推器，飞行间谍车
No，you're quite right。It does sound a bit far fetched.
不，你说得很对，听起来确实有点离谱
Holley！What are you doin' here？
霍莉！你来这儿干什么？
Hello，Mater！It's so good to see you again.
你好，脱线！很高兴再见到你
Finn！
芬恩！
Our satellites picked up an urgent communiqu？
我们的卫星收到了紧急信号？
So you got a my email.
就是说你收到我的邮件了
Y'all is going to have a great time！
你们一定会玩得很开心的！
Everybody，this here's Finn McMissile。He's a secret agent.
各位，这是芬恩·麦导弹，他是秘密特工
Don't tell nobody.
不许告诉别人哦
And this is Holley Shiftwell.
这位是霍莉·灵智速
- She's… - I'm Mater's girlfriend.
- 她是… - 我是脱线的女朋友
It's so nice to meet you all.
很高兴认识大家
Guido believe you now.
这回圭多相信了
Whoa，honey。You got a nasty dent there.
哇，亲爱的，你身上有道很深的凹痕
- Yeah。- Was that from when you swooped in
- 是啊 - 是不是你在伦敦从天而降
and you saved them in London？
去救他们的时候给撞的？
- Van！- What？I'm just asking！
- 老范！- 怎么啦？我就是问问！
Don't you worry。My baby Ramone can get that fixed up for you in no time.
别担心，我的宝贝雷曼马上就能给你修好
Yeah，sure thing。No problemo。Let me go get my tools.
没错，包在我身上，放心吧，我们去拿工具
Oh，no。I'm keeping that dent。It's way too valuable.
哦，不了，我想留着这个凹痕，它很珍贵的
A valuable dent？She's as crazy as Mater.
珍贵的凹痕？她跟脱线一样疯疯癫癫的
Those two are perfect for each other.
他们俩真是天生一对
There's one thing I still don't get.
还有件事我不明白
The bad guys hit me with the beam from the camera，right？
那些坏蛋不是用摄像机的光照我了吗？
- So，why didn't I… - Explode in a fiery inferno？
- 那为什么我没… - 炸成个火球？
- Yeah。- We couldn't figure that out，either.
- 是啊 - 我们也不明白
Our investigation proved that allinol was actually gasoline
我们的调查证实聚合油其实就是汽油
and Axlerod engineered it so when it got hit by the beam，
艾克斯勒洛德改造了它
it would explode.
所以用被射线加热时会爆炸
Wait a second，Fillmore。You said my fuel was safe！
等等，菲尔莫，你说过我的燃料是安全的！
If you're implying that I switched that rot gut excuse for alternative fuel
如果你在暗示我用了个老掉牙的借口
with my all natural，sustainable，organic biofuel
把聚合油换成了我的纯天然可持续有机燃料
just because I never trusted Axlerod，
只是因为我从没相信过那个艾克斯勒洛德
you're dead wrong，man！
那你就大错特错了，兄弟！
It was him！
是他干的！
Once big oil，always big oil，man.
一朝当上石油巨头，永远都是石油巨头，兄弟
Tree hugger.
抱树的嬉皮
The Radiator Springs Grand Prix is about to begin.
油车水镇汽车大奖赛即将开始
All spectators，clear the starting line.
所有观众请离开起跑线
I can't wait to get rockin'。This is gonna be wicked！
我都等不及要跑起来了，比赛一定很刺激！
We should do this every year.
我们应该每年都举办一次
Yeah，I just figured we never found out who the world's fastest car is.
是啊，我刚想起来，我们一直没决出胜负呢
Plus，no press，no trophy，just racing.
而且没有媒体，没有奖杯，只有比赛
- The way I like it。- Francesco likes it like this，too.
- 我喜欢这样 - 弗朗西斯科也喜欢这样
- Francesco，I'd like you to meet… - Signorina Sally.
- 弗朗西斯科，我向你介绍… - 莎莉小姐
It is official.
毫无疑问
Lightning McQueen is the luckiest car in the world.
闪电麦坤是世界上最幸运的车
Why，thank you.
真的吗，谢谢你
Which he will have to be to have a chance against Francesco today！
因为他今天有幸和弗朗西斯科一决高下！
See you at the finish line，Mc… What is that？
终点线见，麦…那是什么？
Is- a good，McQueen。Very funny.
不错嘛，麦坤，真有意思
Was- a funnier when I did it，but it's- a very funny.
没我的那么有意思，不过还是挺有意思
What are you going to do next？Are you going to take off your fenders？
接下来你要干嘛？把你的挡泥板卸下来？
Try it。You'll like it.
试试好了，你会喜欢的
So，he's not so good looking.
看来他也不是那么帅嘛
- Yeah。Nice try。- I'm serious！
- 是啊，谢谢安慰 - 我是认真的！
That's why I love you，Sally.
我就爱你这个，莎莉
- Wish me luck！- You don't need it！
- 祝我好运吧！- 你不需要运气！
Ooh- hm！That Francesco is fine- looking！
嗯哼！那个弗朗西斯科可真帅！
And those open wheels.
瞧那些开放式轮胎
Ooh，I'm gonna have to go get myself some coolant.
喔，我得去喝点冷却剂了
Go，Lightning！
加油，闪电！
- Go，Stickers！- Right on，man！
- 加油，小子们！- 跑得好，兄弟！
- Go get 'em，tiger！- Bravo，bravo！
- 追上他们，老虎！- 加油，加油！
- Go，Lightning，go！- Go，McQueen！Whoo-hoo！
- 加油，麦坤，加油！- 加油，麦坤！噢嗬！
Finn？Time to go.
芬恩！该走了
Siddeley's gassed，geared and ready to fly.
西德已经加好油，挂上档，准备起飞了
- You're leavin' already？- We've got another mission.
- 你们这就要走？- 我们还有其它任务
Just stopped by here to pick something up.
就是顺路过来捎点东西走
Somethin' tells me you're not talkin' about souvenir bumper stickers.
我觉得你们说的一定不是车尾贴纪念品什么的
Her Majesty asked for you personally，Mater.
女王陛下亲自要求的，脱线
- But I told y'all before，I'm not a spy。- We know.
- 可我跟你们说过了，我不是侦探 - 我们知道
Spy or not，
无论是不是侦探
you're still the smartest，most honest chap we've ever met.
你都是我认识的最聪明，最诚实的小伙子
- Don't forget massively charming。- Well，thanks.
- 别忘了还有魅力非凡 - 哦，谢谢
But as much fun as it was hangin' with y'all，this…
虽然跟你们在一起很开心，不过…
This is home.
我的家在这里
That's all right。We understand。But I'll be back.
好的，我们明白，不过我会回来的
You still owe me that first date.
你还欠我第一次约会呢
If there's ever anything I can do for you，just let me know.
要是有什么我能帮忙的，尽管开口
Well，I sure appreciate that。Thank you.
好的，非常感谢
Actually，there is one thing.
实际上，确实有件事
Whoo-hoo！
噢嗬！
Whoo！I'll be doggone！
哇！太好玩啦！
Whoa，whoa，whoa！
哇哇哇！
Thanks，Mater！
谢谢，脱线！
Ha-ha-ha！Whoo！
哈哈哈！喔！
Impossible！
怎么可能！
- Ha-ha！- Mater！
- 哈哈！- 脱线！
Check it out。They let me keep the rockets.
看啊，他们把火箭留给我了
I'll see you at the finish line，buddy！
终点线见，哥们儿！
Not if I see you first！
我先见到你还差不多！
Yippee！
耶！